（改?自真人真事）
（1967年 ??市英伍德）
（北曼哈?的一?街?）
Thank you, Colonel!
??你 上校
Sorry. Hey, come on. Coming through! Coming through!
抱歉 嘿 借? ?一?…
-That's for you. -All I'm saying is,
-?是你的 -我的意思是
I can't remember the last time Chickie paid for a beer.
我不?得奇基上一次 ?啤酒?是什么?候了
Wait, are you calling me cheap?
等一下 你是?我小气？
No, he's calling you a freeloader. Now, where's my change?
不 他是?你蹭酒喝 找回?的?呢？
Thank you.
??
Are you shittin' me?
你在?玩笑吧？
Hey, Noodle.
嘿 面?
When I get off a ship flushed with cash, who picks up more tabs than me?
我?得盆???下船后 ??喝酒的次?比我多？
-No one. -Bingo.
-?有? -可不是
But you haven't been on a ship in three months. Do the math.
但你三?月?上船做工了 你自己算
Can't even go to the Shilling no more, 'cause he ain't paid his tab!
?先令酒吧都不能? 因?他????
Hey, that's bullshit! I can't go to the Shilling no more,
嘿 胡?什么 我不能?先令酒吧
because that's where the Keenan brothers hang out.
是因?基南兄弟?在那里
They still mad about you and their sister?
他???了你和他?妹妹的事生气呢？
I don't know. And I don't wanna find out.
不知道 我也不想知道
Hey, who put this shit on?
嘿 ??了?首?歌？
I did. I love this song!
我?的 我??首歌
I love this song too.
我也??首歌
-This song sucks. -It's not great.
-?歌真垃圾 -是不太好
Hey, Colonel! One more round!
嘿 上校 再?一?
Forget it, Donohue. You're three weeks behind on your tab.
想都?想 唐?修 你已?欠了三周的啤酒?了
This ain't on me! It's on Brendan!
?次不算在我的?上 布?登??
Lucky boy!
你小子真走?
And keep 'em comin'!
喝完???
Hey.
嘿
Get your ass out of bed, you lazy bum! Come on.
?虫 快起床 快?
-Fuck. I'm up. -You're not up!
-?死 我起?了 -你?起?
11:30 mass began ten minutes ago, for Chris-- Get the hell up, Chick!
11?30分的?散十分?前就?始了 看在老…快?我起? 奇基
I went there five o'clock last night.
我昨晚5?去?了
Bullshit. Your mother and I were at the five.
胡? 你母?和我去了5?的?撒
Look at you, sleeping your life away.
瞧瞧你 大白天睡? 浪?生命
I'll stay awake when I'm dead.
我死后?保持清醒的
For God sake's, Chickie. Church started already!
看在老天份上 奇基 ?撒已??始了
Get up!
起?
（周日新? LBJ呼吁??一心支持越?）
-What are you doing tonight, Chickie? -What do you think he's doing?
-奇基 你今晚有什么活?？ -你?得他有什么活?？
It's the same every night with him.
每天晚上不都一?
He's off on a toot. He sleeps all day. He's "Good Time Chickie." Must be fun.
一杯接?一杯 蒙?大睡一整天 他是 “???光奇基” 羡慕?人生啊
Oh, my-- Here we go again.
噢 天…又?始了
You know, being a merchant mariner ain't no pleasure cruise, okay?
你要知道 商船船?的日子 并不是游手好? 好?？
-Yeah. -It's backbreaking work.
-是 -是辛苦?作
Boohoo, Chickie.
奇基 好可怜
So this is my time to kick back and relax a little,
所以?是我放松休息的??
like a professor on summer break.
就像放暑假的教授
Oh, yeah. You're a professor, and your grandmother's Miss America.
? 你的确是教授 你的祖母?是美?小姐呢
Come on. Do we gotta start this again?
??? 又要吵???？
You know what? It's my house. He's gonna live by my rules!
?是我的房子 他就得按我的?矩?
He wants to be a drunk and sleep all day. Maybe he should get his own place!
他要是想每天酗酒、睡? 那就自己找?地方住
Fine. I'll move out.
行啊 我搬出去
That's a waste of money, Chickie.
奇基 那太浪??了
You're out to sea more than half the year.
你一年有大半??都在出海
Catherine, you gotta stop babying the boy.
?瑟琳 你不能再溺?他了
When I was your age, I had two jobs. I had three kids. I had a wife.
我像你?么大? 有?份工作 三?孩子 ?有?妻子
So it's my fault you knocked up Ma in high school?
所以你高中?弄大?的肚子是我的?？
-Hey! -Chickie!
-嘿 -奇基
We got pregnant after we were married!
我是在婚后才怀孕的
Come on, Ma.
老? 少?了
You got married in January. Gerard was born in June. It don't add up.
你?1月?婚 杰拉德6月出生 日子?不上
-It was a leap year. -A what?
-那是??年 -什么年？
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Gerard came early. That's how it adds up.
杰拉德是早? 所以日子?得上
Very common in first deliveries.
第一胎很常?的
Johnny Knopf's dead.
?尼科?普死了
-No. -I just ran into Judy Byrne.
-不 -我?碰?朱蒂伯恩了
She's best friends with his sister, Mo.
她是他妹妹茉最好的朋友
But he just got there.
可是他才到那?
Well, you know, the family can be proud. He died a hero, that boy.
他家人?感到自豪 那孩子死得光?
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
How do I know?
我怎么知道？
Because he died for his country. That's how I know.
因?他是?了祖?而死 所以我知道
For his country to do what?
?了祖?做什么？
Hey, Christine. This ain't the time.
嘿 克莉?汀 ?在不是吵??的?候
Well, when's gonna be the time?
那要等到什么?候？
We don't even know why we're fightin' over there.
我?甚至不知道?什么要在那里打仗
For Chrissakes. Has it ever occurred to you
拜托 你就?想?
our country knows very well what they're doing,
我??家非常清楚自己在做什么
they just haven't told you yet?
只是?告?你而已？
LBJ's lying to us! He won't even admit it's a war!
LBJ?我??? 他甚至不愿承?那是??
-Yeah. Everybody's lying, Christine. -They are lying!
-是 每?人都在?? 克莉?汀 -的确是
Christine, that's enough.
克莉?汀 ?了
Yeah, Ma, it is enough.
? ? 确?是?了
Eight kids from this neighborhood are dead already.
我?街?已?有八?孩子死了
How many's it gonna take before you all wake up?
?要死多少?你?才?醒?？
（?德勒?生酒吧）
The young mother's daughter was shot
年?母?的女儿被??中?
while quietly riding a bicycle with her father.
正在安?地与父?一起??踏?
On a public lane, in a little village.
在一?小村庄的公路上
In the warm sun on a beautiful day.
那是一?晴朗和煦的日子
She will be dead in an hour??
她一小??就?死去…
Knopf wasn't even supposed to be there.
科?普原本都不?去那里
He and his old man signed a waiver so he could enlist at 17.
他和他爸?了免?? 好?他17?就入伍
Jesus. What the hell was his rush?
天啊 他干??么急?上??？
His rush was he was doing his patriotic duty.
他是急?履行??的??
You make a very good point.
你?得很有道理
This is bullshit. They should not be showing this on TV.
真是?? 他?不?在??上播??
This would not fly back in my day.
?在我?那?年代是不允?的
There was no TV back in your day.
你?那?年代根本???
Yeah. And we were better for it.
是 那可比?在好多了
War is not a TV show. It's too real-life.
??不是???目 它太真?了
And the American people can't handle real life?
所以美?人?法面?真?生活？
No, they can't. And they shouldn't have to.
是的 他??法面? 也不?被迫面?
Bringing dead soldiers, guys with no arms and legs,
把死去的?士、四肢不全的人?
into our living rooms
?入我?的客?
is not helping no one.
???都?好?
If they had showed the Battle of the Bulge on TV,
如果?年??上播了突出部之役
we'd have quit after three days.
我?三天就?投降
We didn't. We took our licks, but we pushed 'em back, and we won.
而我??有 我??守、反抗并取得胜利
It was a different time. It was a different war, Colonel.
那是另一?年代 也是另一??? 上校
What are you selling, Noodle? You saying you're on their side?
面? 你是什么意思？你站他?那??？
I'll throw you right the hell outta here.
我?就把你赶出去
Jesus, Colonel. You got a short fuse today, huh?
老天 上校 你今天?真是一?就爆啊？
I ain't got a short fuse. You just don't know when you lit it.
我早就想爆了 只是你不知道 自己是什么?候把我惹毛的
God, I hate these things.
天 真???种事
Why can't they just have a funeral and get it over with?
?什么不能????葬?就完事了？
This just drags it out and makes it worse for everyone.
他?非要弄得又臭又? 大家都不好受
Asshole.
混蛋
The wake is for the family. It's not about you.
守?是?了他家人?行的 又不是?了你
It gives 'em time to grieve and shit before they put him in the dirt.
??他?在下葬之前有??哀悼
You hit it on the head. We need wakes. They're important.
你?到重?了 我?需要守? 守?很重要
It's very good for everyone to grieve.
大家有机?哀悼是很好的
Jesus, Danny. Don't you ever have an opinion that you stick to?
我的天 丹尼 你就??法 ?持一???不???？
-You just blow with the wind, don't you? -No.
-你真是??草啊 -不是
I just try to be open-minded to everybody's point of view.
我只是保持?放的思? 包容大家的意?
Like the way dogs are.
像狗一?
"Like the way dogs are"?
“像狗一?”？
-What's he saying? -I'm just saying dogs don't judge.
-他?什么呢？ -我是?狗不?品??足
The Minogues got a telegram this morning.
米?格一家今早收到??
Tommy's MIA.
?姆在??中失?了
Come on.
拜托
Goddamn it.
?鬼
The ball's dropping in ten minutes. We're gonna miss it, Chick.
十分?后新年大球就要落下了 我?要??了 奇基
Don't worry about it, Tommy. It'll drop again next year!
??心 ?姆 明年??有的
Yeah, but I've never seen it.
? 但我????
-You've never seen the ball drop? -Only on TV.
-你???大球落下？ -只在??上看?
Bullshit.
?人呢
I swear. I've never seen it live, Chick. Just once I wanna be there live.
我?誓 奇基 我??看??? 我只想能目睹一次??
All right, come on. Let's go!
好的 ? 我?走
Goddamn it.
?鬼
Poor Minogue. He was the best.
可怜的米?格 他以前人最好了
Don't say "was." MIA doesn't mean dead.
?用?去式形容他 失?不意味?死亡
If anyone can survive out there, it's Tommy.
要??能在??上活下? 那一定是?姆
He and his brothers, they got those street smarts, you know?
他和他的兄弟?最有街?小?明了
Look at these scumbags.
看看?些人渣
Hey, hey, LBJ! How many kids did you kill today?
嘿…LBJ 你今天?死了多少?孩子？
Hey. What are you doing?
嘿 等等 你干什么？
（唯一的好共?主?分子 是死去的共?主?分子）
Go home! Go home, you commie bastards.
回家…你??些共党混蛋
（停止??）
（?我?的大兵回家）
Hey, man! Stop, man! What are you doing?
嘿 停下 你在做什么？
Those candles represent soldiers who were killed in Vietnam!
?些蜡?代表死在越南的士兵
Sorry. I thought they were peace candles.
噢 抱歉 我以?是和平蜡?
What, you got a problem with peace?
怎么 你?和平有意?？
I got a problem with you, mouth!
我是?你有意? 大嘴巴
These demonstrations are hurting our troops!
?些游行示威??害我?的??
Yeah, why don't you just keep marching right up to Canada
? 你??什么不一直游行到加拿大去
and lock the key behind you?
去了就?回?？
Come on, Chickie. Let's get outta here.
走吧 奇基 我?离??里
What the hell?
搞什么？
How many kids did you kill today?
你今天?死了多少?孩子？
Hey, hey, LBJ! How many kids did you kill today?
嘿…LBJ 你今天?死了多少?孩子？
Hey! Let's go.
嘿 我?走
?夙o of me!
放?我
What the hell are you doing? Go home now!
你在?里做什么？快回家
You're embarrassing yourself, and you're embarrassing your family!
你在?自己的? ?我?家的?
Trying to save more Inwood kids from dying is embarrassing myself?
??拯救更多英伍德的孩子 ?他?不白白送命是?我的?？
That's right. Because this ain't helping nobody.
?? 因???不了任何人
At least I'm trying to get 'em home alive.
至少我在努力?他?活?回家
Everyone's doing something, and you're doing nothing.
每?人都在出力 而你什么都?做
Doing nothing?
什么都?做？
I served four years in uniform, starting when I was 18 years old.
我曾服役四年 18??就?始了
You were playing poker in a military base in Massachusetts.
你那?是在麻省?事基地玩牌
You weren't dodging bullets, you were dodging bar tabs.
你?未躲避??林?雨 你只?躲避酒吧??
So quit acting like you've been there!
所以?假?自己上???
Come on. You know what? Screw you!
得了吧 去你的
Now, let's go.
快跟我走
I'm not going anywhere with you!
我才不跟你走
I'm gonna be here every day until this war's over,
我每天都???里 直到???束
because this war is immoral!
因?????不道德
Don't tell us about immoral, all right?
?和我??道德不道德 好?？
We're burying Johnny Knopf tomorrow, and Tommy Minogue's MIA,
我?明天要埋葬?尼科?普 ?姆米?格失?中
and you're out here marching with the enemy?
你?在?里和?人游行？
-Tommy? -Let's just go home, please?
-?姆？ -我?回家吧 好?？
Don't tarnish Johnny's memory like this.
?玷污了?尼的回?
"Tarnish his memory"?
“玷污他的回?”？
I'm doing this to honor his memory, you dumb shit!
我?么做是?了?念他 你?只蠢?
I don't wanna see no more kids die for nothing!
我不想再看到更多孩子白白送命
For nothing? They died to save us from communism!
白白送命？他?是?了 保?我?不被共?主?侵?才死去
This war isn't about stopping communism, it's about spreading imperialism!
????与阻止共?主??? 它是?了散播帝?主?
Hey, cool-breeze. Shut the fuck up!
嘿 潮男 ?我?嘴
-You shut up! -Yeah. Don't push us into your war.
-你?嘴 -是 ?逼我??你打仗
-Fascist pig! -You're the problem, man!
-法西斯? -你才是??
What the-- My war?
?什么屁…?我打仗？
I'm just here looking out for my friends, who, by the way,
我在?里是?了??我的朋友 ?提一句
-are over there fighting for you! -Exactly!
-他?正在?你?作? -??
We don't need your friends killing for us, man!
我?才不需要你的朋友?了我??人
You know what, baby killer? You and me, let's go!
?儿?手 ??吧 我??一?高下
I don't wanna fight, man. This march is about peace.
我不想打架 哥? ?是?于和平的游行
To hell with your peace! Come on. You and me, let's go!
??你的和平去死吧 ?啊 你和我 ?真的
-I'm not gonna fight you. -Stop it.
-我不?和你打架 -?吵了
You don't have a choice! I'm gonna hit you in about three seconds.
由不得你 我三秒后就揍你
But I'll give you the first crack.
但我?你先出手
Go ahead, give it your best shot.
?啊 用?全力
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Don't you do it, Chickie, don't!
奇基 ?打 不要
-You asshole! -Stop! Stop it!
-混蛋 -住手…
Hey! Back off! Back off!
嘿 后退…
Stay there! Hey! Back off!
?? 嘿 后退
Hey, Christine!
嘿 克莉?汀
Christine!
克莉?汀
Take a shower!
去洗?澡吧
Those pussies had us outnumbered 10-to-2, and we still kicked their asses!
?些?包人多 我???打他?十? 但?是痛扁他?
So how'd your cheek get all swelled up?
那?什么你的腮?子都?了？
Sucker-punch. Some hippie. That's what started it.
我揍了某?臭嬉皮 所以才?起?
Do these dumbass protesters not know that our soldiers see that bullshit on TV
那些白痴抗?者不知道 我?的士兵?在??上看到?些事
and that it's broadcast all over the world?
而且是在全球播出？
And this is exactly what the enemy wants.
?正是?人想要的
To see us divided. Fighting.
看到我?分裂、??
If Americans can't agree,
如果美?人?法?成共?
it makes it look like they're right, and we're wrong.
看起?他?就是正确的一方 我?是??的一方
I just wish our guys could see
我只希望士兵?能看到
that the vast minority of the country's behind them.
美??是有少?群?是支持他?的
-You mean vast majority? -Well, no. I wouldn't go that far.
-你是?大多?吧？ -不是 我?事求是
I think most people are behind them, yeah, sure.
我?得大部分人支持他? ?然
But not everyone.
但不是每?人
You know what I'd like to do? I'd like to go over to Vietnam
你?知道我想做什么?？我想去越南
and track down Reynolds, Collins, Pappas, Duggan, Minogue.
找到雷??、柯林斯 帕帕斯、杜根、米?格
You know, all the boys in the neighborhood.
我?街?的所有兄弟?
And just give them a beer, you know? To say thank you.
然后?他?一罐啤酒 知道?？表示感?
To the boys!
敬兄弟?
-To the boys! -The boys!
-敬兄弟? -兄弟?
I could do that.
我可以
Do what?
可以什么？
Bring 'em beer.
?他?送啤酒
I could sign up for a ship headed to 'Nam. Drop off a few brews.
我可以申?在前往越南的船打工 送些啤酒?去
Are there even boats going over there with the wars going on?
??期?有船去那??？
Hell yeah. Who do you think's bringing 'em supplies?
?然了 要不然??他?送??品？
Are you serious, Chick?
奇基 你是?真的？
You can just hop on a merchant marine ship and drive over there?
你可以就??跳上某艘商船 ?船?去那里？
Of course he's not serious. He's hammered. Look at him.
他?然不是?真的 他喝醉了 瞧他??子
The man's stone sober. That's his fifth beer, maybe, tops.
他清醒得很 那可能是 他的第五罐啤酒 ?多了
Don't bullshit us, Chick. Could you really pull this off?
奇基 你?逗我? 你真的能做到?？
Could, would, and will. That's a promise.
能、?、一定 ?是我的承?
I'm gonna show 'em that this neighborhood and this country is still behind 'em.
我要?他?知道 我?街?和我?的?家仍支持他?
What Chickie's saying is important.
奇基?的很重要
It's very important.
非常重要
It'll prop our boys up.
???我?的兄弟?士气大振
Maybe a good ol' American beer will remind them
也?一罐地道的美?啤酒能?他?想起
what they're fightin' for.
他??斗的初衷
Thank God someone knows.
感?老天?有人知道那是什么
You bring it to 'em in this. That way they know it's from all of us.
你用??? ??他?就知道 ?是我?大家的心意
We're bringing the boys beer.
我?要?兄弟?送啤酒
Hey, Chickie? Chickie, don't do this. Tell 'em you're full of shit.
嘿 奇基…??? 告?他?你??的
-It's always harder afterwards. -Okay.
-早?坦白更容易 -好的
Get me a list of all the guys and the units that they're in, okay?
把每?人的名字和所在的部? ?我列?清? 好?？
Because I'm going to Vietnam, and I'm bringing them beer!
因?我?去越南 我要?他?送啤酒
-Yeah! -Yeah! Let's go!
-好 -好 我??吧
God bless you, Chickie.
上帝保佑你 奇基
Those brave bastards over there, fighting and dying for this country.
那?混蛋在英勇作? ?了祖?抗?、就?
We're sitting on our asses doing nothing. Except for you.
我???所事事 除了你
Yeah. Well, I ain't done nothing yet.
是 我?什么都?做呢
The hard part's gonna be finding a ship.
最?的是找到去那?的船
Then, once I get over there, how am I even gonna track 'em down?
然后 到了那?后我要怎么找到他?？
Shouldn't be that difficult. Small country, right?
不?太? 那?家很小 ?吧？
Shitload of trees, though. It's like an African jungle over there.
但有很多? 就像非洲?林
Hey, McFadden just got back from 'Nam. I bet he's got a map.
嘿 ?克法登??越南回? 他一定有地?
He could show you where they're all stationed.
他可以告?你???扎?在哪
Right, but like I said, getting there's the real problem.
是 但就像我?的 如何去到那里是真正的??
Even if I do find a ship, what if they're fully staffed up? They--
就算我找到船 如果已???了呢？他?…
Chickie! When you're in Vietnam, you're gonna visit my son, right?
奇基 你去越南后?找我儿子吧？
-Well-- -127th MP Company.
-?… -第127?兵?
See, it's right there on the patch on his shoulder.
瞧 就在他的臂章上??呢
He'll be so excited to see a friendly face.
他看到老熟人的?一定?心极了
Yeah, there's still a few kinks to iron out, Mrs. Collins.
是 但?有些???敲定 柯林斯太太
Like, I don't even know if it's possible for me to get over there.
我?不知道能不能去到那里
And when you see him, please give him a hug for me.
你和他?面后?代我?他一??抱
Jesus, those guys are putting the horse way in front of the cart.
天啊 ?些人高?得也太早了
What do you mean?
什么意思？
I never said I was going to Vietnam, I said I was gonna try to go.
我???我要去越南 我只?了??量
No, I'm pretty sure you said you was going and that you was bringing beer.
不 我很肯定你?的是 你一定?去 你?要送啤酒
Yeah. If there was a boat.
? 如果找到船
Yeah, I don't remember that part.
是 我不?得你?了??
Shit, Noodle. Read between the lines!
?鬼 面? ???我的言外之意
How the hell can I control if there's a boat or not?
有?有船又不是我?了算
-Okay. -No, it's not okay.
-好吧 -不 一?也不好
'Cause now I'm gonna look like an asshole if I don't go.
因??在我不去的? ?人??得我是?混蛋了
-To who? -To those guys.
-???得？ -那些人
Don't worry about those guys. They don't really think you're going.
??心那些人 反正他?也??得你真?去
They're just busting your balls.
他?只是在逗你
What? They don't think I'm going?
什么？他?不?得我?去？
Well, you're not going, right?
你并不?去 ?吧？
That's beside the point. Why do they think I'm not going?
那不是重? 他??什么?得我不?去？
Well, no offense, but, come on, Chick.
恕我直言 可是 奇基 拜托
There's a lot of things you say you're gonna do
有很多事是你???做
that you don't get around to doing 'cause, you know, you get busy.
但?果?做的 因?你懂的 你?在忙
What things I ever say I was gonna do I didn't do, huh?
哪些事是我???做但?果?做的？
Seriously. Name one thing.
?真的 ?一?例子
You never became a cop.
你??警察
And you never played shortstop for the Yankees.
你??成?洋基?的游?手呢
-What? -It was fifth grade.
-什么？ -那是五年?
I said I was gonna be a cop.
我?年?要?警察
What, you're not allowed to change your mind after fifth grade?
五年?后不能改?人生理想了?？
That doesn't count.
那不算?
Well, you never graduated high school.
你?有高中??
When did I say I would?
我有??????？
You never sold peanuts at the Polo Grounds.
你?有在?球??花生
Because the day I was gonna start,
因?我要?始?的那天
Patty Benedetto gave me a way better job loading rigs at Empire Trucking.
帕蒂?涅德托?了我更好的工作 在帝???公司?搬?工
Yeah, but then you quit that job one day after.
? 但你一天后就??了
So it's my fault the boss was an asshole?
老板是混蛋也怪我了？
Well-- Look, Chickie, all we're saying is, you don't have to go to Vietnam.
听? 奇基 我?只是想? 你不是一定要去越南
It's not like people really expect you to.
大家也不是真的指望你?去
Let's go.
走吧
So when were you gonna tell us?
你打算什么?候告?我?？
You know, that you're bringing beer to your friends in Vietnam.
你要?越南的朋友?送啤酒
Richie Reynolds's girlfriend, Jeanie, dropped these socks off.
瑞奇雷??的女友珍妮送??些?子
She already mailed him a few pairs, but he never got them.
她已??他寄了几? 但他?收到
So she wants you to hand deliver 'em.
所以她希望你?手送?他
And Mr. Collins dropped off 33 bucks for Tommy,
柯林斯先生??姆送?33美元
so he could pay back his poker losses and he wants you to tell him to stop.
好?他?清玩牌?的? 他要你告??姆??了
So, I'm just curious, how many pops in were you
所以我很好奇你??下肚了几罐酒
when you came up with this brilliant notion?
才想出??金?子啊？
So Christine, you saying I'd have to be drunk
克莉?汀 你是?我必?喝醉了
to wanna support my friends in Vietnam?
才想到支持我在越南的朋友?？
How would bringing beer be supporting them?
送啤酒算哪?子的支持？
It's about friendship and loyalty, something you know nothing about.
??乎友?和忠? 是你毫不了解的?西
If you really want to support them, help us get 'em the hell out of there.
要是你真想支持他? 那就?我? ?他?离?那里
Oh, my God. You're like a broken record.
老天啊 你就只???句??？
You know, I can't-- The thing I can't figure out
你知道 我不能…有一件事我想不明白
is how he's gonna get all the Clydesdales on the boat.
就是他怎么把那么多 克??代?啤酒弄上船
You three, don't laugh at him.
你?三??笑他了
You'll talk him into this foolishness and get him killed.
你??激得他做蠢事 害他送命
Stop it, Catherine.
??了 ?瑟琳
No one's ever gotten killed sleeping till 3:00 in the afternoon.
睡到下午3?是不?送命的
Chickie's fine.
奇基不?有事
Mrs. Minogue. I--
米?格太太 我…
Chickie, I hear you're going over to visit the boys.
奇基 听?你要去看孩子?
I want you to bring this to Tommy when you see him.
我希望你把?????姆
-Yeah, come on in. Just, come on in. -No.
-是 ??吧 ??坐坐 -不用了
I want to drop these off.
我只想把?些送?
They can't find Tommy right now?? but I'm sure they will.
他??在找不到?姆 但我肯定他??找到的
No, please, Mrs. Minogue, you hold onto those, all right?
不 米?格太太 ?些?你留? 好?？
If I end up going,
如果我最?真的去了
then I'll come and pick 'em up from you, okay? I promise.
那我??去和你取的 好?？我保?
No. You see, Tommy said that he brought some,
不 是?? ?姆?他?了一些
but I bet he didn't.
但我打?他??
Anyway, having two sets can't hurt, right?
?之 有?套?是有??患的 ?吧？
No, I guess not.
的确
Thank you, Chickie.
??你 奇基
Hey, chief.
嗨 老大
No chance you have a ship heading to Vietnam any time soon, right?
你近期不?有船去越南 ?吧？
That cargo ship, Drake, getting ready to push off.
（甲板 引擎 乘??）
那艘?船 叫德雷克的 即?出?
No shit. What time?
逗我呢 什么?候？
1700 hours.
下午5?
Tonight?
今晚？
-What, in three hours? -Yeah.
-三小?后？ -?
Goes out of Jersey, straight to Panama, then straight to 'Nam.
??西?航 直接去巴拿? 然后直接去越南
Should be there in two months or so.
????月左右到
But I doubt they need an oiler this late in the game?
但???候了 他?不?需要油匠吧？
Oiler.
油匠
Hey, you're in luck. They're still one short.
嘿 你走?了 他??缺一名
And why are they going out of Jersey?
他??什么??西出?？
She's loaded with 10,000 tons of ammo.
船上??了一万吨??
Blow up half of Manhattan if something went sideways.
如果出什么差? 半?曼哈?都?炸?
If Jersey goes up, who'd miss it?
如果炸?的是?西 ????？
You want in?
你要上船?？
（??啤酒）
（德士）
Chickie!
奇基
You can't be serious?
你是?真啊？
What?
什么？
Please don't do this. This is the dumbest thing I ever heard.
??去 ?是我听?最蠢的事
Dumber than carrying around signs, calling our friends baby killers?
比??牌游行 ?我?朋友是?儿?手更蠢？
Don't give me that shit. I wasn't carrying that sign.
?扯?些 我??那?牌
Yeah, but you were marching with someone who was.
是 但和你一起游行的人?了
Just imagine being a soldier,
想象你是一名士兵
just got home and that's the first thing he sees,
回到家?后最先看到的
is that sign.
是那??牌
Please, Chick.
拜托了 奇基
-You're gonna get yourself killed there. -No, I'm not.
-你去那??送命的 -不 我不?
Yes, you are! I don't get it. Why are you doing this?
你?的 我不懂 你?什么要做?件事？
It's like you said. Everyone's doing something.
就像你?的 每?人都在?自己的一份力
I'm doing nothing.
我什么都?做
Three days' leave? You got some nuts on you, Donohue.
?三天假？你?真有种啊 唐?修
Nobody gets three days.
?人能?三天假
What about the engine room? That's gonna run itself?
引擎室怎么?？??操作？
Sir, I worked double-time the whole way here,
?官 ??里的路上 我每逢假日都加班
and I got all my shifts covered, sir.
?有??一?班 ?官
I don't give two shits.
我不在乎
And don't talk to me like we're in the marines, you butt-licker.
?用海????那套 ?和我?? 小狗腿子
No one's getting off this ship. We're in a goddamn war zone.
?也?想下船 ?里是?死的??
But I have to.
但我必?下船
You have to? What's your deal, Donohue?
你必?？唐?修 你有什么理由？
I need to find my stepbrother. Ricky Duggan, First Air Cav.
我必?找到我的?弟 瑞奇杜根 第一空??兵?
Stepbrother? He's not your goddamn real brother?
?弟？他不是你的?弟弟？
No way. You ain't getting three days for a half-ass brother.
不行 ?想?了 只有一半血?的兄弟休三天假
I got a rust bucket to run here.
?艘破船?得要人看?呢
But he is my real brother, sir. My mom is his mom.
但他是我的?弟弟 ?官 我?是同母兄弟
You know, my dad died fighting in Okinawa.
我爸在???亡
And, you know, my mom remarried and Ricky was born,
我?再婚 生了瑞奇
and we was raised together, just like real brothers.
我?一起?大 如同?兄弟
You know, I just got word my stepdad, Ricky's dad, just died.
我?听?我的?父 瑞奇的爸爸?去世了
I don't want Ricky to read the news in a letter
我不想瑞奇通?信件得知消息
or hear about it on a phone call.
或是通???得知
I would like to tell him in person.
我想?口告?他
How'd he die?
他是怎么死的？
Stroke.
中?
Linger?
?留了？
Yeah. Like a week or two. It got real ugly at the end there, so??
是 拖了一?周 到最后情?很糟 所以…
Where's this stepbrother?
你???弟在哪？
He's up north. The LZ??Jane.
他在北面 ????
Christ.
我的天
Shit's hit the fan up there. You could be walking into a bloodbath.
那?情?很?劣 你??直走?血流成河的??中
You know that, right?
你明白吧？
Well, he's my brother.
他是我的兄弟
You get all the info on the stepbrother and all that,
你有?于?弟的所有信息?？
in case Donohue gets his balls blown off stepping on a land mine?
以防唐?修踩到地雷 把自己炸?
Yeah, all right here.
是的 都在?里
Okay. You got three days.
好的 ?你三天??
It's 8:05. If you're not back here in 72 hours and one second,
?在是8?05分 如果你72小?后 ?有准?回?
you better be dead.
你最好已?死了
Yes, sir. You have my word, sir!
是 ?官 我向你保? ?官
（?警）
Hey, you guys ain't with the 127th MP Company?
嘿 你?是第127?警?的?？
Yeah, and what about it?
是啊 怎么？
You don't happen to know a guy named Tommy Collins from New York?
你???一? 叫?姆柯林斯的人?？?自??
Yeah, we know Collins.
是 我???柯林斯
-No shit? -Yeah.
-?真??？ -?
Yeah. You wouldn't know where I could find him, would you?
是 ??我能在哪里找到他？
-Why? -I just brought him a couple of beers
-找他干?？ -我?他?了几罐啤酒
from New York.
?自??
Seriously, pal, why you looking for Collins?
?真的 哥? 你?什么找柯林斯？
No, I'm being serious. I--
不 我是?真的 我…
This whole thing's full of beer from back home.
?包里??了家?的啤酒
Now, listen, smart-mouth. You looking to take a swim?
听好了 耍嘴皮的 你是想被??海里游一圈?？
No. Guys-- Look, I ain't messin' with you.
不 ?位 我不是在和你??玩笑
I'm serious. This-- Here.
我是?真的 ?…?
In fact, you know what? I got a couple for you too.
??好了 也?你?二位几罐
（西? 美???第一后勤指?部）
（???助指?部）
Hey, Pete. He's good. Let him in.
嘿 皮特 他??? 放他?去
Hey, buddy. He is in there somewhere.
嘿 伙? 他就在里面某?
-Thanks, guys. -All right.
-??你? -好
All right, which one of you donut holes wants to get your ass kicked first?
好了 你?几?蠢蛋 ?想先被煮熟了吃啊？
-The fuck you say? -You heard me, cupcake.
-你?什么鬼?？ -你听到了 小家伙
What, you think that uniform makes you tough?
怎么 穿了??就以?自己是硬?？
Come on, bring it on. I'll stuff you right in that helmet.
?啊 放??? 戴??盔我也能揍扁你
Chickie, Chickie, Chickie! What the hell are you doing in here?
奇基…你怎么???里？
You know, I was just in the neighborhood.
我?巧路??里
No, seriously. What are you--
不 ?? 你?什么…
Guys, this is my buddy from back home, Chickie Donohue.
各位 ?是我老家的好兄弟 奇基唐?修
Yeah.
是
Got some pretty screwy friends, Collins.
柯林斯 你的朋友?真是怪胎
Without a doubt. Guess what?
??的 你猜如何？
This screwy friend just came 10,000 nautical miles
?位怪胎朋友航行了十万海里
to deliver your ass a sudsy thank-you card.
?你?送一?起泡的感??卡
Like my grandfather used to say,
像我???去??的
always ring the doorbell with your elbow.
永?不要空手上?
And that, my friends, is called the Irish hello.
我的朋友? ?就是 ??中的???式?候
-Here. Take that. -Hello, Ireland.
-? 拿好了 -你好 ???
Hello.
你好
Take it.
拿?
I still can't believe you came all this way just to bring me a beer.
我?是不敢相信 你?么???只?了?我送啤酒
Not just you.
不只是你
I came for Duggan, Reynolds, Pappas. All the guys.
我?要去找杜根、雷?? 帕帕斯 所有兄弟
-That's the dumbest thing I ever heard of. -Really?
-我??听??么蠢的事 -真的？
Is it dumber than the time you took a pull off your nephew's baby bottle,
蠢?你那次喝你侄女的奶瓶
'cause you wanted to know what titty milk tastes like?
因?你想?母乳的味道？
That was your sister's titty milk?
你姐姐的母乳？
No, it was my brother's wife's. I'm not an asshole.
不 是我嫂子的母乳 我不是??
Hey, hey. Wait, wait.
嘿…等等…
So, I got this from your old man, $33 to pay off your poker debt.
?是你老爸?我捎?你的 33美元 用??扑克?
-Thank you. -Almeida, what the hell--
-?? -埃?米? 搞什么…
Uh-uh. Now we're even, buddy.
?在?清了 伙?
What the hell's going on here?
?是在做什么？
Attention!
立正
Where'd those beers come from?
?些啤酒是哪?的？
Who the hell are you?
你是什么人？
I'm Chickie Donohue.
我是奇基唐?修
And what the hell are you doing here?
你在?里做什么？
Just got off a ship, sir.
?下船 ?官
Am I talking to you, Collins?
柯林斯 我在和你???？
What's your business?
你是做什么的？
Just traveling around.
只是周游四?
Be more specific.
?得具体?
Okay. More specific-- I'm traveling around Viet-- In Vietnam,
好的 具体?…我在越南旅游
and I'm bringing beers
我要送啤酒
to as many of my friends from my neighborhood as I can.
?我街?的朋友? ?量?每?人都送到
You're traveling in country? Alone?
你在越南旅游？一?人？
Yeah. That's right.
? ??
Understood.
明白了
As you were.
稍息
-He seems like an okay guy. -He's not.
-感?他人不? -并不是
Did he just have a stroke?
他?是中?了?？
Nah. Don't you get it?
不 你不懂?？
He thinks your man Don Ho here is a "tourist."
他??你朋友唐?修是“游客”
What do you mean? I am a tourist.
什么意思？我是游客啊
-Tourist is what we call CIA. -CIA? Get the hell outta here.
-游客是我??中情局的代? -中情局 少?了
Man, who else but CIA would be headed up-country,
哥? 除了中情局 ?有??北上
dressed like they're going on a golf trip?
穿得像要去打高?夫球一?？
No, Erickson's right.
不 艾瑞克森?得?
The military brass does not like to mix it up with CIA.
?方高?不想和中情局打交道
Yeah, that's the quickest way to get your ass reassigned
? 一不小心就?被?到
to combat patrol.
?斗?查?
You're kidding me. He thinks I'm CIA? Like James Bond?
不?吧 他以?我是中情局的？ 像詹姆士邦德？
Well, in that case??
??的?
Yeah, come on!
好 ?呀
-Reynolds is over there. -Yeah.
-雷??在那? -是
Duggan's up here somewhere and Pappas is--
杜根在?里某? 帕帕斯在…
He's right around the ammo dump, right here.
他就在???附近 ?里
So??I mean, what's my plan of attack, I guess?
所以 怎么? 我的作??划是什么？
How much time you got?
你有多少??？
Forty-seven hours.
47小?
It's gonna be tight.
??很?
What if he starts up here with Duggan and then hustles down to??
如果他??里?始 先去找杜根 然后南下去找…
-Reynolds. Yeah. -?吐eynolds.
-雷?? ? -雷??
And then back down to Pappas?
然后 再掉?去找帕帕斯？
Why? I don't understand. How come I just can't go see Pappas first?
?什么？我不懂 ?什么我不先去找帕帕斯？
'Cause I can practically see his base from here.
因?我在?几乎都能看到他的基地
Nah, Baby-Face is right.
不行 嫩?蛋?得?
Pappas might be the closest, but he is furthest in time.
帕帕斯也?最近 但去他那里最久
Long Binh's the biggest ammo dump in this country.
隆平是越南最大的???
They'll be doing background checks.
他??做背景?查
Ask about your high school girlfriend, count your hemorrhoids--
?你高中的女友的事、?你的痔??…
Christ, it would take Westmoreland half a day to get in there.
天 就算是威斯特摩? 都要被??半天才能?去
-Go see Duggan and then the other guy?? -Reynolds.
-去找杜根和另一?… -雷??
?地nd if you're still alive and you have time,
如果你?活?、?有??
then you can hit Pappas on the way back.
那就可以在回?的路上找帕帕斯
That's right. How you getting there?
? 你打算怎么去？
I don't know. I figured I'd hitchhike.
不知道 我想搭便?
What? You don't have a plan?
什么？你?想好?划？
Are you kidding me?
你在逗我?？
How would I have a plan?
我怎么?有?划？
It's not like you can hire a tour bus out here. Can you?
?里又不能租旅游巴士什么的 可以?？
-Jesus Christ. -I don't know.
-我的老天? -不知道
What if he caught a plane to LZ Jane?
乘?机去????怎么?？
Go airplane?
?机？
How's he gonna do that? He ain't military.
他怎么乘?机？他不是?方的人
Wait, wait. Why can't I just hitchhike? Isn't there still roads?
等等 ?什么我不能搭便?？ 不是?有公路?？
I don't know if it's hit the papers back home yet,
我不知道??媒体?道了?有
but folks are getting their asses shot in these parts.
但?片?的人??遭??
Are you guys nuts?
你??了?？
Give me that thing.
?我
Stop helping him. What are you trying to do, get him killed?
??他了 你?想干什么 害他送命?？
Chickie, you gotta get the hell out of here.
奇基 你必?离??里
Yeah, okay. I'll get my shit. I don't want to get you guys in trouble.
是 好 我?收拾行李 我不想?你?惹麻?
No, I mean out of 'Nam.
不 我是?离?越南
Yeah, I will. In a few days, as soon as I see the other guys.
是 我?的 几天后 找到其他兄弟就走
You can't be serious about this, Chick.
??玩笑了 奇基
Come on, man, you did it. You got me hammered in Vietnam,
拜托 哥? 你成功了 你?我在越南喝得大醉
and I'm sure we're gonna have a lot of laughs about this forever.
?件事?我?笑一?子的了
Let's quit while we're ahead, huh?
?好就收 好?？
I didn't come all this way just to quit after one night.
我?么???不是?了睡一?就放?的
What am I supposed to do? Let you go out there like a babe in Toyland
我?怎么做？任你去 像玩具????那?
and get your brains blown out like Knopf did?
然后像科?普那?被爆?？
You're worrying way too much.
你也想得太多了
I'm not gonna be fighting no one, I'm just deliverin' beers.
我不?上?? 我只是送啤酒
You don't get it, do you, Chick? This isn't a John Wayne movie, all right?
奇基 你?不明白 是?？ ?不是?翰?恩的?影 好?？
Where you know who the good guys are and the bad guys are.
?是好人、?是坏人 一目了然
This is guerrilla warfare,
?是游??
and they can come at you from anywhere, at any time.
他????地都?扑上?
Bringing beers into a fucking war zone? That's a batshit crazy idea.
去?死的??送啤酒？ ?是?子才想到的主意
I mean, you didn't really think you can pull this off, did you?
你不?真?得你能成功吧？
But why the hell you think I came all the way to 'Nam?
那你?得我?什么大老?地跑?越南？
I don't know, Chick! You lost a bet, you're runnin' from the cops,
我不知道 奇基 你??了、躲避警察
you knocked someone up-- I can't figure it out!
你搞大了?的肚子…我猜不到
Chickie, even if you wanted to do this, there's no way for you to get around.
奇基 就算你有心想做 你也不可能通行
The only non-military people who can travel the country
能在越南四?移?的非?方人?
are the press.
只有媒体的人
Well, where are they? I'll go talk to them.
那他?在哪？我去和他?聊聊
They're at the Hotel Caravelle,
他?在卡拉威?酒店
but they're not gonna help you. You're a civilian.
但他?不??你 你是平民
I'm an American civilian. I'm one of them, you know?
我是美?平民 我是他?的一分子吧？
No, you're not. You're nothing like them.
不 你不是 你和他??有任何共同?
I think you're forgetting who you're talking to, yeah?
你是不是忘了自己在和???？
It's me, Chickie.
是我 奇基
Look, you just guard the ships, okay? I'll handle the press.
听? 你只管看守船 媒体就交?我?理
No, thank you. It's okay.
不了 ??你 不用了
Thank you. Thanks.
??你 多?
You American?
你是美?人？
Yeah. Yeah.
是…
You from Oklahoma?
你?自?克拉荷?？
No. New York.
不是 ??
Near Oklahoma?
在?克拉荷?附近？
No, not really. Not even close, actually.
不 不是 其?挺?的
Like Oklahoma! Good movie.
我喜?《?克拉荷?》 很好的?影
Yeah. Good football too.
? 橄?球?也很棒
MacRae, great actor.
?克雷 很棒的演?
Gordon MacRae. Yeah. Yeah, he is. He's very good. Very good.
戈登?克雷 ?…他是很棒 非常棒
Hey, do you know where the Caravelle Hotel is around here?
嘿 你知道卡拉威?酒店在哪?？
Two down, on left.
???路口 左手?
-Safe to walk. -Okay.
-可以走了 -好的
Hey, Oklahoma?
嘿 ?克拉荷?
Thanks a lot!
非常感?
（卡拉威?酒店）
Hello. My name is Hien. How may I help you?
你好 我叫? 有什么能?你?？
A whiskey soda, please.
一杯威士忌?打 ??
Whiskey soda on the way.
威士忌?打 ?上就好
（山姆卡斯蒂安 《看?志》）
（拜?海? 伯?德法?）
（皮特范提? 自由??者）
（黃成密 美?社）
Boy, this is one hell of a place to watch a war from, right?
天 在?里看?? ?真是?特的体? ?吧？
War, it's far. But managed here in Saigon.
??很? 但西??里??得去
Hey, do you know where I can find any of the reporter guys around here?
嘿 你知道在哪能找到?者?？
Press? Throw dart, hit press guy.
媒体？?便扔???就能?中一?
Right. Hey, thank you.
好的 嘿 ??你
Hey, how's it going?
嘿 你好?？
I'm American.
我是美?人
And I find an attitude of confidence and growing optimism.
我感受到自信的氛?和??情?的蔓延
It prevails all over the country.
?种情?在全?盛行
This is bullshit. Are you hearing this?
真是胡扯 你听到了?？
Westmoreland's saying there's a feeling of optimism all over Vietnam
威斯特摩?? 越南全?上下都充?了??主?
and that the Communists are running for the hills.
共党被打得???退
Finish up your drinks, chaps. Time to go home.
各位 快喝完 ?回家了
A number of South Vietnamese living in areas
今晚 在受政府保?的越南南部地?
under government protection tonight has grown by more than a million
居民?量增加超?一百万
since January of last year.
与去年1月相比
Turn that lying asshole off.
?了 不想看那混蛋?子
Hey, I don't appreciate that.
嘿 ?不好
That's the President of the United States you're talking about.
你?的可是美???
He deserves some respect.
他???得尊重
Why?
?什么？
All right, look. Look, I don't care
好吧 听?…我不在乎
what you think of him personally as a person,
你?人?他有什么看法
but you gotta respect the Office of the President of the United States.
但你必?尊重任美???的人
I mean, look who he is.
看看他的身份
You expect us to respect the man who's telling the American people
你?得我???尊重一?告?美?民?
we're actually winning the war?
我?打???的人？
And that we, the media, are keeping it a secret?
他??我?媒体?此保密
If the shoe fits.
如果事?真如此的? 是啊
Hien.
?
One more time for Jesus.
再?我一杯 看在耶?份上
So, tell me.
那么 告?我
How did you become such an expert on the public relations of war?
你是怎么成???公??家的？
I'm not an expert, and I never said I was one.
我不是?家 我???我是
Thanks for the disclaimer.
多?你的免??明
Hey, mister, people back home get their news from you guys.
嘿 ?位先生 祖?的群? 是?你??里?取新?的
And look, let's face it, it ain't all been that positive lately.
听? 我????? 最近的新?都不太正面
Why should it be positive?
?什么要正面？
You don't understand why it's important
你不理解其中的重要性？
that people back home get positive news about the war?
???群?得到?于??的正面消息
No. I don't.
? 我不理解
So they don't lose hope. It's going crazy out there, and you--
??他?就不?失去希望 ?在????瘴气 而你?…
You're takin' the wind out of everyone's sails.
你??大家失去信念
You're riling up protesters, it's--
你?煽?抗?者 ?在…
Look, I'm just saying,
听? 我只是想?
you might wanna support our boys every once in a while.
你?偶?也可以支持一下我?的??
Telling the truth about this war is being supportive of our boys.
?出????的真相 就是在支持我?的??
Well, it sure don't come across that way on my TV.
我???上看到的可不是??
How are you supporting them?
那你是怎么支持他?的？
I support 'em in??
我支持他?的方式是…
in, like, many ways, in lots of different ways.
有?多 各种各?
Yeah, that's what I figured.
是 我猜也是
Okay, for one thing,
好的 其中一?
I just traveled 12,000 nautical miles to bring all my enlisted friends a gift.
我?航行了一万?千海里 ?我所有入伍的朋友送?物
What kind of gift?
什么?物？
Beer. Beat that.
啤酒 比不?吧
Beer?
啤酒
They can get beer here, you know?
你知道?里也有啤酒吧？
Yeah, but not American beer.
? 但不是美?啤酒
Yeah, but this beer came all the way from New York. So??
? 但?些啤酒 是我大老??????的 所以…
Listen, the beer's not the point.
听? 啤酒不是重?
The point is that I'm trying to show them
重?在于我想?他?看到
that somebody back home still gives a shit.
???有人在乎他?
Well, I give him credit.
我得承?
It may be idiotic, but it's a noble gesture.
?然很白痴 但?是?高尚的??
Well then, do you think you guys can help me out?
那你?有可能??我?？
Listen, I need to hop a plane to LZ Jane.
我需要乘?机去????
You know what? I think I can swing it.
你?? 我可能?真?得上忙
I could maybe book you a flight out of Bien Hoa.
我?不定能?你安排?机离??和
What's your preference? You want like a window seat? Aisle?
你有什么偏好？窗口位？走廊位？
I don't care.
我?所?的
Hey, you wanna go first-class? Meal service?
嘿 要不要坐?等?？送餐服?？
Anything you want, kid.
想要什么都行 孩子
Sorry, buddy.
抱歉了 伙?
Why don't you just pack up your beer, take it back to your frat?
你?是拿上你的啤酒 回你的兄弟?吧
Besides, they won't even let us up there.
而且他?都不?我?北上
Don't let them get to you. You'll never win.
?把他?的?放在心上 你?不?他?的
But they're right about one thing.
但他?有一件事??了
Impossible to get around in my country right now.
此刻是不可能在我??家四?走的
Military travel only.
只有?方能出行
Military, huh?
?方啊？
（美???）
-Where you headed? -I'm trying to get to??Bien??
-你要去哪？ -我想去…?…
Bien??The air base.
?…空?基地
-Come in. I can take you. -Yeah?
-上?吧 我能?你去 -是?？
Thanks.
??
（美?空?）
Hey, thank you!
嘿 ??你了
Just go inside and up the stairs.
?去 然后上?梯
Hey. Do you have a plane heading to LZ Jane?
嘿 你?有去????的?机?？
I can get you most of the way there. Then you're gonna have to chopper in.
我可以送你大半程 但之后你得坐直升?机?去
Okay. Go ahead and put my name on the manifest. It's John Donohue.
好的 把我的名字?在乘机名?上吧 我叫?翰唐?修
-Donohue, you said? Right. -Donohue. Yeah. John Donohue.
-唐?修 是?？好 -唐?修 ? ?翰唐?修
And what's your rank, sir?
先生 你的??是？
I'm not military.
我不是?方的人
Well, that's gonna have to be cleared with the captain, sir.
那我得向上尉?? 先生
Okay. You can go get him.
好的 你去找他?
Get him!
去找他?啊
Yeah?
什么事？
You the guy trying to get to LZ Jane?
是你想去????？
Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
是的…?
You're a civilian?
你是平民？
Yes. As far as you're concerned.
? 你?我是就可以
It's one of you guys.
是你?啊
Why didn't you say so, Private?
大兵 你?什么不?一?？
Put the gentleman's name in the manifest immediately!
立即在乘机名?上?下?位先生的名字
Yes, sir.
是 ?官
As soon as they're done unloading the bodies, you can get on.
他?把尸体卸下?后 你就可以登机了
Right.
好
John Donohue?
?翰唐?修？
No.
不是
Sorry. I must have gotten the name wrong.
抱歉 我一定是??名字了
Captain Dyer in Saigon instructed me to be of assistance in any way I can.
西?的戴耶上尉 指示我?可能?你提供?助
Oh, yeah. Dono??Donohue, yeah. But they call me "Chickie."
? 唐?…修 ?? 但大家一般叫我“奇基”
So, he told you to help me?
他?你?助我？
Yes, sir. He's my superior officer.
是的 先生 他是我的??上司
They shuffle me between here
他?派我往?此地
and Tan Son Nhut air base, right outside Saigon.
和西?城外的新山一空?基地
Habershaw, Lieutenant Habershaw. Yeah.
我是哈勃肖中尉 ?
-Let me get that for you, Mr. Donohue. -Thank you.
-我?你拿 唐?修先生 -??你
So, what can I do you for?
有什么能?你的?？
Well, I need a lift to LZ Jane.
我要乘?机前往????
Not a problem. I can have a bird ready for you in 60 minutes.
??? 我可以在60分?? ?你安排好?机
Really?
真的？
Yeah, perfect.
好的 太棒了
Have you eaten, sir?
先生 你吃了?？
No, I have not. How's the food around here?
??有 ?里的伙食如何？
It'll make a turd, sir.
不至于?人吐出? 先生
That sounds great.
听起?棒极了
I'd be honored to have you join me in the Officer's Club for lunch.
若你愿意和我一起去?官俱?部 用午餐 我?很?幸
A friend of mine would love to meet you.
我的一?朋友一定很想?你
You know what? Thanks, Habershaw, I'm just--
?? 你的好意心?了 哈勃肖 但…
After that flight, I just don't have that much of an appetite.
?了?一程后我?什么胃口
-You sure? -Yeah.
-你确定？ -是
We carry the best scotch this side of Tokyo.
我??里有?京那? 最好的?格?威士忌
The??
你是?…
So, what department are you guys in?
（越南 ?港空?基地 末日俱?部 ?官自由聚餐?）
你?是哪?部?的？
Army transport service, in conjunction with mortuary services.
????部 与?葬部??
We move bodies.
我?搬?尸体
Our soldiers. KIA. In caskets.
用棺材?我?的?亡士兵
That must be hard,
??任?一定很?吧
dealing with the dead all day.
每天?理尸体
I don't think about it much, sir.
先生 我不?想太多
I'll have plenty of time to think about it all later.
我之后有的是??去想
So, any chance you can brief us a little about what you guys are planning?
你有?有可能和我?透透口? 你?有什么?划？
-You can trust us. -Come on, Habershaw.
-你可以信任我? -拜托 哈勃肖
If he could trust us, he wouldn't be a very good CIA agent. Now, would he?
要是他信任我?了 就不是一?优秀的中情局特工了 ?吧？
That's true.
那倒是
Not that I am a CIA agent.
不是?我是中情局特工
By the way, I wasn't the one who told Fusco who you are.
?提一句 不是我告?弗斯科你的身份的
That came from Captain Dyer in Saigon.
是西?的戴耶上尉?的
I would never blow your cover.
我??不?暴露你的身份
I see a lot of shit, and it all stays right in here.
我??的大?大雨多了 全都放在?里
Everything.
每一件事
I got a lot of shit in here.
?得????
So, come on. Can't you give us just a hint?
所以 拜托 不能??提示?？
You know, tell us without telling us?
用暗??一?？
All right. Let's just say??
好 我就?么?吧
I'm here to deliver beer to a friend.
我是??一位朋友送啤酒的
Beer? To who?
啤酒？??？
A friend in Bravo Company. First Air Cav.
一?B?的朋友 第一空中?兵?
Keg?
桶?？
Cans.
罐?
Wow, that's gonna be a shit show, isn't it?
我的老天 ?可是一?苦活啊？
It's been a pleasure meeting you, sir.
??你很高? 先生
If you and your people ever need any help. Any help.
如果你和你的同事需要任何?助 ?客气
I mean, like, if you ever need to get something out of here or back in,
比如需要把什么?西?出或?回?里
and you need it to be under the radar, I'm your guy.
不能??的那种 悉听尊便
Good to know.
多?告知
-Can I ask you a question, sir? -Shoot.
-先生 能?你一????？ -?管?
If someone wanted to do what you do,
如果某人想做你的工作
how does one go about getting noticed by Langley?
那人要怎么引起?利的注意？
-Langley? -Headquarters.
-?利？ -?部的
How do the big boys at the CIA find you?
怎么?中情局高??掘你？
Just be a good soldier and a good person.
做?好士兵、做?好人就可以了
I am, sir. If it's not asking too much,
我正是如此 先生 如果不?太唐突
do you think you could maybe put in a positive word for me?
能否?你?我??好?？
Which helicopter am I getting in?
我的直升机是哪台？
-Straight ahead. -Okay.
-正前方 -好的
So, you think you could? Put in a good word?
你能?忙美言几句?？
Okay, sure.
好 ?然
Thank you, sir. I very much appreciate it.
先生 多?了 非常感?
Do you need my name and company?
需要我的名字和?????？
No, we'll find you.
不用 我??找到你
Lt. Gill Habershaw. 528 Support Battalion.
吉?哈勃肖中尉 第528后勤?
That'll make it easier.
?下更容易找到了
-Who the hell is this guy? -I don't know.
-?家伙是?？ -不知道
-I'm looking for Rick Duggan. -Who?
-我在找瑞克杜根 -?？
Rick Duggan.
瑞克杜根
-You got orders? -No.
-你是奉命而?？ -不
Let me see your papers.
?我看看你的公文
I don't have any.
我?有公文
No orders, no papers. Mission classified?
?有命令、?有公文 机密任?？
Goddamn it! They never tell me shit.
真是?鬼 他?什么都不跟我?
Call Duggan in from the ambush post.
把杜根?伏??召回?
Tell him he's got a visitor.
告?他有人找他
What's your name, sir?
先生 你叫什么？
Just call him in. I kind of wanna surprise him.
叫他回?就好 我想?他一?惊喜
Romeo-45, this is Romeo-06, over.
R45 ?是R06 完?
This is Romeo-45.
?是R45
Duggan, report to TOC ASAP, over.
杜根 立即到??行?中心?道 完?
Right now?
?在？
That's 200 meters, and our situation's hot. Over.
距离有200米 而且我???正交火 完?
Right now.
?在
While it's still light out? Over.
天??黑的?候？完?
That's affirmative. Out.
是的 完?
He's on his way.
他在?的路上了
Okay. That's good.
好的 很好
This is good.
很好
Okay. I'm gonna hide here. And you guys cover me with this.
好 我藏在?里 你?用???我?上
No.
不
Okay.
好吧
-You wanted to see me, Sarge? -No.
-?士 你有事找我？ -不是
Chickie?
奇基？
-What are you doing here? -I brung you beer.
-你在?里做什么？ -我?你?了啤酒
-Who are you with? -I'm with you.
-你是跟??的？ -我跟?你啊
Seriously, Chickie, what the hell are you doing here? Really.
我?真的 奇基 你在?里做什么？?真的
Me and all the fellas were sitting around
有天我和兄弟?坐?
talking about what we could do to bring your spirits up.
??要怎么?你?鼓舞士气
And then, bang! It hit us. Bring you a beer. So, I brought you a beer.
然后?光一? 我?想到了 ?你?送啤酒 所以我送?了
-You dumb shit! -What?
-你?白痴 -什么？
You almost got me killed out there!
你差?害我在外面送命
Wait a minute, Duggan. You mean to tell me this asshole's a civilian?
等等 杜根 你是??混蛋是平民？
Yeah. Yes, Sarge.
是的 ?士
Is he nuts?
他是?子?？
I don't know. Chickie, are you nuts?
不知道 奇基 你?了?？
What? No.
什么？?有啊
-You're delivering beer in a battle zone? -Yeah, so? It's fine.
-你跑到??送啤酒？ -? 所以呢？?事啊
I just came from seeing Collins. He didn't mind.
我???柯林斯 他就不介意
You found Collins?
你找到柯林斯了？
Yeah.
?
It was easy. He was right next to my ship in Saigon.
不?找 他就在西? ?扎在我的船附近
After this, I'm going to visit Reynolds and Pappas.
之后我要去找雷??和帕帕斯
By the way, a lady tried to sell me a snake on the way over here.
?了 ??里的路上 一?女士想??我一?蛇
-You think this is funny? Huh? -What?
-你?得很好笑？ -什么？
-It's not funny at all! -I don't think it's funny, okay!
-?一?也不好笑 -我不?得好笑 好吧
I'm not doing this for laughs, Ricky!
我做?件事不是?了好玩 瑞奇
I'm doing it for you, for all you guys.
我是?了你 ?了你?所有人
This is a goddamn war, Donohue. You shouldn't be here.
唐?修 我?正身??? 你不????里
Chickie, get back to your boat right now.
奇基 立即回你的船上去
Forget about the other guys. You can buy 'em a beer when they get home.
?找其他人了 你可以等大家回家?再?他?喝啤酒
This is serious shit out here.
?里不是??玩的
Yeah, I know.
是 我明白
No. No, obviously you don't, or you wouldn't be here!
不…你?然不明白 否?你不???里
You keep on this stupid beer run, there's a 99% chance you're going tits up.
你要是???趟送啤酒之旅 你有99%的可能???子
Sarge, can we get a egg beater in tonight and, you know, scoot him out of here?
?士 今晚有可能安排直升机 送他离??？
It's too dangerous. Nothing's flying till morning.
?在太危? 明早才?有?机
So what am I supposed to do with him?
那我要拿他怎么?？
Hell if I know. He's yours now. Take him with you.
我哪知道 他?你管了 你把他?在身?
What-- I'm on ambush post, sir.
什么…?官 我正?守伏??
Your problem, Duggan!
杜根 你的麻?你?理
You want a taste of Vietnam?
你想??越南的味道？
You're about to get it. Grab your shit.
?上就能?到了 拿上你的?西
-Grab your shit! -I am.
-拿上你的?西 -正在拿呢
Hey.
嘿
Thanks.
??
-What's this for? -To shoot the bad guys, dodo.
-?是用?做什么的？ -用?打坏蛋 小菜?
If it looks like you're gonna be taken for prisoner,
要是?得你快被?人??
shoot yourself or they'll torture you for info.
朝自己?? 否?他???你逼供
For info? Hold on. I don't have any info.
逼供？等等 我?什么可提供的
They don't know that, asshole!
他?又不知道 混蛋
Okay, geez. A bit edgy.
懂了 天啊 脾气真爆
No. Bad idea, Sarge.
不 ?士 坏主意
He's got a better chance of shooting one of us than one of them.
他更有可能打中自己人 而不是??
What are you talking about? I know guns. I was in the military.
你?什么呢？我?用? 我曾服役
-Where'd you serve? -Massachusetts.
-你在哪里服的役？ -麻省
Yeah, give me that.
好的 ??我
Are you ready?
准?好了？
I guess. What are we doing?
??吧 我?要怎么做？
We're gonna run for our lives.
撒丫子逃命
All right.
好
-We're halfway home. -Halfway?
-只剩一半路了 -一半？
On the count of three, follow me. One--
?到三就跟我走 一…
Wait.
等等
-What? -Let's go back.
-怎么？ -我?回?吧
Just as bad going back as it is going forward.
回?和向前一?糟
Then let's just stay here.
那我?就留在?
Here? We're in no-man's-land.
?里？?是?人?
So? I'm okay with that.
所以呢？我?得挺好啊
We gotta keep going.
我?必?前?
Can't we just call a tank or something?
就不能叫一?坦克之?的?？
Tank-- There's no goddamn tanks out here.
坦克…?里才?有什么坦克
All right. On the count of three.
好吧 ?到三
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Oh, shit!
?死的
Oh, God. Oh, shit.
老天 ?鬼
All I could think about??
我??子都是…
"What if these are the last moment of your life?"
“万一?是你??子的最后一刻呢？”
And all I could think was,
我??子?是
"I hope they're aiming at the asshole in the checkered shirt."
“希望他?瞄准的是穿格子衫的混蛋”
Relax, relax.
???…
One of your beers just exploded.
你的一罐啤酒爆了
Just a beer. Just a beer.
不?是啤酒…
Duggan, where's the Starlight scope? We got a lot of movement on the perimeter.
杜根 夜??在哪？周?有不少??
What's going on? Are we okay?
怎么了？我??事吧？
NVA are out there moving around.
北越?正在四?移?
-NVA? -Probably just passing by.
-北越?？ -可能只是??
But if they attack, boogie on back to the line post.
但要是他??? 就后退到前?哨所
Okay. The line post is??
好 前?哨所是…
-Back where we came from. -Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
-?才?的地方 -是…??
Tell them to turn on the lights. Let's see what's out there.
?他?打?? 看看那?情?
India-26, this is Romeo-45.
I26 ?是R45
We need illumination forward of our position. Over.
我?需要前方照明 完?
Copy that, Romeo-45. Illumination inbound.
收到 R45 即?照明
Who's this hand job?
??物是?？
Hi.
你好
He's my next-door neighbor. He brought me a beer.
他是我的?居 他?我送啤酒?了
What the hell does that mean?
?是什么意思？
It means he jumped on a freight in New York.
意思是他在??上了一艘?船
Came all the way out here. Bring me a beer.
一路航行到?里 ?我送了一罐啤酒
-Seriously? -Yeah.
-你?真的？ -?
Wait a minute. Are you telling me you don't have to be here,
等等 意思是你本不需要??里
and you're here?
但你??了？
Yeah.
?
Yo.
How many beers you bring?
你?了多少罐啤酒？
A bunch.
很多
Now would be the time to pass them out.
?在是分?大家的好?机
Yeah?
是?？
Busker.
巴斯克
Sorry, they're a little warm.
抱歉 有?暖
That is good.
不?
Reynolds is dead.
雷??死了
What?
什么？
Got word a few days ago.
几天前收到的消息
No.
不
Goddamn it.
真?鬼
We never saw that kid without a smile on his face.
每次?到那小子 他都在笑
Yep.
?
Any word on Minogue?
有米?格的消息?？
No.
?有
Now, let's get some sleep.
?在睡?儿吧
Where?
在哪睡？
Here. What, are you expecting a Howard Johnson's?
?里 怎么 你?想住霍?德?翰?酒店？
Throw this on if it gets rainy.
下雨的?就?上??
You really Duggan's next-door neighbor?
你真的是杜根的?居？
Yeah.
?
Couple of apartments over,
只隔了几?公寓
but close enough to hear his old man yelling at him.
但近得能听?他老爸吼他
He was a yeller.
他嗓?很大
Where you from?
你是哪里人？
Philly.
?城
How long till you go home?
你?有多久能回家？
I don't really keep track anymore.
我已?不再算日子了
You don't wanna jinx it?
你不想??嘴？
I went home after my first tour.
我第一次服役?束后回家了
I didn't fit in.
?法融入
So, I came back.
所以我回?了
Twice.
?回折?了?次
I'm way more at home here.
?里更有家的感?
Christ.
天啊
Come on. Time to go.
好了 ?走了
Is it over?
?束了?？
Yeah, you're dead.
? 你死了
That wasn't so bad.
也?那么糟嘛
Okay, guys. We're heading out.
好了 各位 我?出?
Wait, hang on. One second.
等等…?急
One breakfast beer, first.
先?一罐早餐啤酒
-All right, just one. -Thanks.
-好的 就拿一罐 -??
Hey, fellas. Smile.
嘿 各位 笑一笑
-Hey. -Here you go.
-嘿 -?
-Thank you. -This is great.
-?? -真不?
-Anyone else? -Yeah.
-???拿？ -好
Here, for your scrapbook.
? 可以?在你的剪?簿上
-Don't peel it open for 90 seconds. -Got it.
-等90秒再撕? -明白
Thank you, sir.
??你 先生
What's he doing?
他在做什么？
What?
什么？
Just smoking a jay?
抽大麻？
What if the sergeant finds out?
要是?士??了呢？
The sergeant probably sold it to him.
?不定就是?士??他的
Look, Chick.
听我? 奇基
Me and my guys are happy as shit you brought us beer.
我和?友?很高?你?我?送?啤酒
It's the first time I've seen a couple of the asswipes smile in weeks.
?是几周?我第一次 看到他?中的一些人笑
But we're going out on patrol today, and you can't come with us.
但我?今天要出?去巡? 不能?上你
I mean, hell, you don't wanna come with us.
我是? 你?不想跟?的
All right, there'll be choppers coming in on the LZ in two to three hours,
好 ?、三小?后?有直升机????
once this shit clears up.
等??散了之后
Try to grab the first one out of here.
你趁早乘一台离??里
Yeah.
好
Okay.
好的
Hey. I got something for you.
嘿 我有?西要?你
Reynolds's girlfriend wanted me to give these to him.
雷??的女朋友?我把??捎?他
Guess you could use them.
我想你能用得上
That's not a rock you're sitting on. That's elephant shit.
你坐的不是石? 是大象?便
VC trains them to move equipment.
越共??大象????
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的？ -?
Promise me you'll go right to your boat, Chick. End it here, please.
答?我你?直接回船上 奇基 你?趟行程就到此?止吧 拜托了
Yeah. Yeah, okay.
好的…行
And I kind of got to go anyway. I'm running out of time.
其?我也得走了 我快???了
Duggan, let's go. We're moving out!
杜根 走了 我?要出?了
Be right there, Sarge.
?上? ?士
Well, thanks for coming all the way out here, Chick.
多?你大老?找到?里 奇基
You're probably the only crazy bastard on earth to do something like this.
你大概是地球上唯一一? ?做出?种事的?子
-Hey, stay safe, Ricky. -Yeah.
-嘿 保?好自己 瑞奇 -是
I'll see you back in the neighborhood.
我?回家?
Don't worry about him.
不用?心他
Every once in a while you run into a guy who's too dumb to get killed.
?世上?有些人啊 蠢得想死都死不了
-Hey, can you take me to Saigon? -Is that where you're bringing him?
-嘿 你能?我去西??？ -你?要?他去那里？
Bringing who?
??？
（美???）
Where's the rest of them?
其他人呢？
He said, "Who?"
他?：“?？”
Listen, Charlie, I want names now. Who's been helping you?
听好了 越共 ?在 就把名字供出? ?是你的同伙？
He says, "I don't know anything."
他?：“我什么都不知道”
Okay. Strap in!
行 系好安全?
Time to see if this piece of shit can fly!
是?候考?一下?垃圾的?行能力了
Now!
?吧
Hey!
嘿
You've got ten seconds or you're going out the door! I'm serious!
?你十秒? 否?就把你扔下去 我?真的
What the hell are you doing?
你在做什么？
Who's been helping you?
?是你的同伙？
He swears he don't know anything.
他?誓什么都不知道
Well, tell him he better make something up,
告?他至少??什么
or he's going out!
否?就把他扔下去
Come on, man! Just tell him to tell him what he wants!
拜托 哥? ?他?他想听的就好了
We got it!
他招了
Okay! Take her down!
好 降落吧
（昆嵩机?）
（?自上天的?）
What's this? This isn't Saigon.
?是哪？?不是西?
The hell you talking about? Your partner told me to land at Kon Tum.
你?什么呢？你的同伴?我在崑嵩降落
Who are you again?
你是???？
-Just a tourist, like you! -Yeah?
-只是?游客 和你一? -??啊
Who's your travel agent?
你找的是哪家旅行社？
Same as yours.
和你的一?
I'll tell the boss you say hi.
我??你和老大?好的
（昆嵩?行操作部）
Sorry, sir. I can't find nothing going to Saigon.
抱歉 先生 我找不到去西?的?机
Well, keep looking, okay?
??找 好?？
I need to be at the harbor by 8:00 a.m. So I need to get out by tonight.
我必?早上8?前到港口 所以今晚就得出?
I could ask the helicopter you came in on if he could take you to Saigon.
我可以??你??乘的直升机 是否能?你去西?
No, I can't go on that.
不 我不能上那台
Somebody blew their lunch all over the place. It's disgusting.
有人在机上把午?吐得到?都是 很?心
What about those ones?
那些呢？
They're down.
都出故障了
Got a couple mechanics driving in from Pleiku air base to pitch in.
波?古空?基地的几位机械工 ?????修理
We'll set you up with a bed in the barracks,
我?可以在???你准?床?
-get you out tomorrow afternoon. -I just told you. I have to be back--
-明天下午就送你离? -我??了 我必?在…
Pleiku, do they have choppers?
波?古那?有直升机?？
Sure, it's a helicopter base.
?然 那里是直升机基地
-Well, how far is it? -Twenty-four klicks due south.
-离?里多?？ -南部24千米
-In American. -About 16 miles.
-?英? -大?25公里
-Well, can you get me a lift there? -Not tonight, sir.
-能找??送我去?？ -今晚做不到 先生
But I can get you a ride back with the mechanics tomorrow.
但我可以安排你明天 和机械工一起坐??去
-What if I walk? -Sixteen miles?
-如果我走路呢？ -走25公里？
-Yeah. I could hitch, you know. -Not advisable, sir.
-? 我可以沿路搭便? -先生 ?不明智
The VC own the night on that road.
晚上那?路是越共的地?
All right. Give me a second. Let me see what I can do.
好 ?稍等 我再想想?法
Thanks.
??
Anything?
怎么?？
No, but tell you what.
?有 但??吧
I'll give you a lift over to Pleiku myself.
我??送你去波?古
Really? You can just leave your post like that?
真的？你就??离????？
Yeah. As long as I'm back in an hour or so, I should be okay.
?事 只要一小?左右回?就好
Amazing. Which way's your head? I gotta take a leak.
太棒了 洗手?在哪？我得小解
Last door on the left.
左手?最后一道?
I'll meet you out front.
我?外面?
Thank you.
??你
Shit! He's running! Let's go!
糟糕 他逃了 快走
All right. Let's get out of here.
好吧 我?走
Raquel Welch is with us tonight. Pretty young lady.
今晚我?有幸?到 拉寇儿薇芝 呃 美?的姑娘
Oh, yeah.
是
Yes. I'll drink to that.
是 值得干杯
You'll drink to that?
值得干杯？
You'll drink to a??
干杯是?了…
You know. "There's a tree. I'll drink to that."
你懂的 “那里有棵? 值得干杯”
What do you think, Chick? Am I doing the right thing enlisting?
奇基 你?得呢？我入伍是?的???？
Of course you're doing the right thing, Tommy.
?然是?的?? ?姆
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, I think I'm doing the right thing too. Yeah.
是…我也?得?是?的
But sometimes, you know??
但有?候 你知道…
What?
什么？
Everything, you know.
所有?一切
The whole thing is-- It's confusing.
?整???…?人摸不清??
I mean, all the shit you hear about what's going on over there,
?于那??生的事有各种?法
and everyone's got a different point of view.
人?各持己?
Who does?
比如?？
Like my uncle Leo.
比如我叔叔里?
He was a flamethrower in World War II.
他在二??是?火器操作?
Even he said he wouldn't fight in Vietnam,
就?他都?自己不??加越?
because he doesn't even know who the Nazis are over there.
因?他都不知道????中?是?粹
There's still Nazis?
?在?有?粹啊？
The bad guys.
意思是坏蛋
Who are we even fighting, huh?
我?到底在和?打仗？
Well, that would be the Reds, the commies.
?然是??、共党
The guys who want to come over and take over everything.
想??走一切的人
Yeah. When I was talking to your sister's friends,
是 我和你妹的朋友聊?
they said just the opposite thing.
他??的完全相反
They said there are no bad guys. It's just a revolutionary war.
他???有坏蛋 ?不?是一?革命??
And the people we're there defending,
我?上??保?的人
they don't even want us there in the first place.
打?一?始根本就不希望我??去
Minogue, don't listen to my sister's friends.
米?格 ?听我妹朋友瞎?
I told you-- Columbia morons.
我和你??…哥?比?的白痴
Hey, Tommy.
嘿 ?姆
You're going over there to defend the United States of America.
你去那里是?了保?美?
How could that possibly not be the right thing to do?
?怎么可能是?的事？
Yeah, you're right, Chick. Yeah, you're right. You're right.
是 你?得?? 奇基 ? 你是?的…
You fuckin'--
?死的…
No! Don't shoot!
不 ???
Don't shoot!
???
Chickie? Chickie fricking Donohue?
奇基？奇基唐?修？
Who's that?
是?啊？
-It's McLoone! -Who?
-是?克?恩 -?？
Kevin McLoone from Dyckman Street! Jesus! What the hell are you doing here?
戴克曼街的?文?克?恩 天啊 你怎么?在?里？
Loony?
?尼？
You know this guy?
你???家伙？
Yeah, we used to play CYO basketball together.
? 我??去是基督青年??球?的?友
Chickie, what the hell? Why are you-- Am I dead?
奇基 搞什么？你?什么…我是死了?？
Why are you in the middle of the jungle in the middle of Vietnam?
你?什么?出?在越南的某??林里？
Long story. But the CIA, they're after me, man.
???? 但是中情局在追捕我
-But-- -They're trying to kill me.
-可是… -他?想?了我
The-- What are you talking about?
中情…你在?什么？
The Central Intelligence Agency.
中央情?局
-They're after me, man. -So you came to Vietnam?
-他?在追?我 哥? -所以你跑?越南？
No, I came to deliver Duggan and Reynolds and the other Inwood's guys beers.
不 我是??杜根、雷?? 和英伍德的其他兄弟?送啤酒的
Wait, beers? What do you mean, beers?
等等 啤酒？啤酒是什么意思？
I thought it would be nice to bring them all beers.
我?得?大家送啤酒挺好的
But now the CIA is after me,
但?在中情局要抓我
because I saw shit that I wasn't supposed to see.
因?我看到了不?看到的?西
What did you see?
你看到了什么？
They were throwing people out of helicopters.
他?把人?下直升机
-How'd you know it was CIA? -Because I was in the chopper with them.
-你怎么知道是中情局的？ -因?我在他?的直升机上
Wait. You're CIA?
等等 你是中情局的？
No. No, what? No, no, no, no, no. They thought that I was one of them.
不…什么？不是…他?以?我也是中情局的
That's because a major came up to me.
因?我遇到一?少校
He saw how I was dressed, so I just-- I went along with it.
他看到我的衣? 所以我就…?水推舟
They-- For a second, it--
他?…某一刻…
Then they started throwing people out the helicopter.
然后他??始把人?下直升机
And this kid, he said he could drive me all the way to Pleiku,
然后有?小子?可以??送我去波?古
like he could just leave his post.
二?不?就擅离?守
But I knew it was bullshit. I knew it was bullshit. He was setting me up.
但我知道有鬼…他在?我下套
There was a foot long caterpillar climbing up my arm,
有一?30厘米?的毛毛虫爬上我的手臂
on my face, almost in my mouth.
爬到我?上 差?爬?嘴里
-Okay, buddy. -It was seriously--
-好了 伙? -??真的…
Hey, take a breath. Look, get in the Jeep, Chick.
嘿 歇口气 瞧 你先上吉普? 奇基
We got to get the hell out of here before we get killed.
我?必?在被?之前离??里
-Come on. -Okay.
-走吧 -好的
Sorry, guys.
抱歉了 各位
Can you take me to Pleiku so I can catch a chopper?
能送我去波?古?？我得乘直升机
Right now we're heading to Kon Tum.
我?在去崑嵩的路上
-Just a few miles up. We got to fix-- -What? No, I can't go back there.
-?有几公里就到 我?得修… -什么？不行 我不能回去
-That's where the CIA is. -For Chrissakes.
-中情局的人在那 -我的老天?
I have to get to my ship in Saigon right away.
我必?回到我在西?的船上
I'm sorry, man. We got orders. We got to get up there.
抱歉 兄弟 我?有命令 我?必?去那里
All right, fine. Then I'm out.
好 行吧 那我下?
Hey.
嘿
Come on, Chick. Please get back in the Jeep.
拜托 奇基 ?回到吉普上?
We'll get you back to Saigon,
我??送你去西?
and we'll make sure the CIA doesn't get you.
我??确保中情局不?抓到你
No. I'm not going back to Kon Tum.
不 我不要回崑嵩
I'm not messing around, Kev.
我不是??玩 ?文
I'm in big trouble if I don't get my ass out of this country.
如果不离???家 我的麻?就大了
Look, man. We don't got no choice, all right?
听我? 兄弟 我??有?? 好?？
We got to go fix those helicopters,
我?必?去修直升机
and if you stay out here alone, you're a dead man.
如果你?自上路 一定??命的
I'll take my chances.
我愿意冒一下?
-Don't be an asshole! Come on. -No, you don't be an asshole!
-?犯? 拜托 -不 犯?的是你
You know me, Loony. Why would I make up a story like this?
?尼 你了解我 我?什么要???的故事？
Please. Kev.
拜托 ?文
Mason, turn it around.
梅森 掉???
Thank you.
??你
Hey, what happened to those elephants back there?
嘿 ?才那些大象是怎么回事？
Napalm. It's a miracle anything survives out here.
凝固汽油? 在?里 有任何生命生?都是奇?
（香薰和薄荷）
I'm sorry about this, Kev. I really appreciate it.
我很抱歉 ?文 ?次真??你
Hey, it's not every day you get to help a secret agent in need.
嘿 ?助秘密特工解?的机? 不是每天都能遇到
Hey, Chick.
嘿 奇基
I'm real sorry about Tommy Minogue. I know how tight you guys were.
?于?姆米?格 我很?憾 我知道你?感情很好
It's not over yet. They just haven't found him.
???束 他?只是?找到他
Yeah. Okay.
是的 好
Stay safe, Loony. I'll see you back in the neighborhood.
?尼 你保重 我?回家?
Hey, Kev.
嘿 ?文
Thank you so much. Thank you. Thank you.
非常感? ??你…
The Drake wasn't supposed to leave till tomorrow.
德雷克???明天才离?的
Intel picked up chatter. Enemy planning a raid.
情?部得到消息 ????划突?
With all that ammo on board, we unloaded her first.
船上?了那么多?? 我?就先?它卸?了
She's halfway to Manila by now.
它?在正在去?尼拉的途中
But she can't leave. I'm her oiler. I run the engine room.
但它不能离? 我是油匠 我??操作引擎室
Well, apparently she doesn't give a shit.
?然那艘船不在乎你
How can I catch up with it then?
我要怎么追上它？
How fast can you swim?
你游泳速度多快？
This ain't funny, man.
?不好笑 哥?
Can you call the ship or something and just tell them to stop?
你能和船??一下 ?他?停下?？
No, I can't, man.
我不能 哥?
Just give me a break.
拜托??我
I'm a civilian, and I just need to get out of this war.
我是平民 我只是需要离????
Well, you're gonna find out it's a lot harder to get out of a war
你???离???
than it is to get into one.
要比?入???得多
My suggestion, go to your plan B.
我的建?是采用后??划
I don't have a plan B.
我?有后??划
Well, off the top of my head, I'd say you're borked.
那我只能?你完了
Oklahoma! Oklahoma!
?克拉荷?…
New York. Happy New Year.
?? 新年快?
Thanks. You're about a month too late, but--
?? ?了一?月的祝福 但…
No. Tonight T矇t eve. Vietnam New Year.
不 今晚是除夕 越南新年
Right. Well, hey, happy New Year.
是 嘿 那祝你新年快?
Hey. Which way's the US Embassy from here?
嘿 美?大使?怎么走？
Right around the corner. Cannot miss.
?角就是 不???
What corner?
哪??角？
Come on. I show you. Nobody listen me here anyway.
? 我?你去 反正?里也?人听我指?
After war, I visit Oklahoma.
?后我要去?克拉荷?
Really?
真的？
Well, I doubt there's a direct flight from here to Oklahoma,
我想?里不?有去?克拉荷?的直航
so, why don't you stop over in New York, and I'll buy you a beer?
所以不如你中途在??停一下 我?你喝啤酒？
Okay. New York people nice? Friendly?
好的 ??的人好?？友善?？
The best.
最友好了
Just don't look them in the eye on the sidewalk,
只要?在路上直?他?的眼睛
or you might have to fight them.
否?他?可能?和你打架
There your embassy.
那?是你的大使?
Thank you.
??
Hey. What New York street you live on?
嘿 你住在??哪?街上？
You serious? You're really coming?
你是?真的？你真的?去？
Unless you not serious?
除非你不是?真的？
No, I'm serious. Yeah, I'm more serious than you.
不 我是?真的 ? 我比你更?真
Hey, here's my address.
嘿 ?是我的地址
And this is my phone number. Give me a call. This is great.
?是我的???? ?我打?? ?太好了
You can stay with me and my family.
你可以住在我?家
You'll meet my dad. He's a real ballbuster. You'll like him.
你可以??我爸 他很凶 你?喜?他
I'm Chickie, by the way.
?了 我叫奇基
Hieu.
我叫孝
-Hieu. Nice to meet you. Thank you. -Thank you, Chickie.
-孝 很高???你 ?? -??你 奇基
Thank you.
??你
See you in New York.
我????
See you there.
???
Name.
姓名
Donohue. John Donohue. I'm American, I'm a merchant mariner.
唐?修 ?翰唐?修 我是美?人 我是商船船?
My ship, the Drake, left early. Something about chatter.
我的船德雷克?提前离港 据?接到什么了情?
Anyways, it took off without me, so I'm in a real jam here.
?之 它?等我就走了 所以我?在有大麻?了
You're right here. I got a file on you.
?里有你 ?有你的?案
Great.
那太好了
The captain of the Drake left a message for you.
德雷克?的船??你留了?
And??
?…
The captain said if you're not dead, he'll take you back on the ship
船??如果你?死 他愿意?你回船上
if you can catch up with it.
如果你能追得上船
Well, I'm not dead. So??
我?死 所以…
Not dead.
?死
So, sorry. Hold on. What's going on? How do I catch up with it?
抱歉 等等 ?是什么意思？ 我怎么追上船？
You sit.
你坐下
I can get you on a flight out of Bien Hoa Air Base to Manila
我可以安排你在?和空?基地 乘坐?机前往?尼拉
tomorrow night at 1900.
明晚7?
Thank you.
??你
Come by tomorrow morning after 10:00, and I'll have your papers.
明天上午10?后?? 我?准?好你的文件
Tomorrow morning after 10:00.
明天上午10?后
You're the greatest. Thank you.
你人太好了 ??你
Hey. Do you mind if I lay down just for 20 more minutes?
嘿 我能再在?里躺20分??？
Then I'll be out of your hair, I swear.
然后我就走 我?誓
Great. Thank you.
太好了 ??
For the first time in five years,
五年?第一次
firecrackers are ringing in the Lunar New Year.
??新年又?起了爆竹?
The South Vietnamese Government have??
南越政府…
I hope you have a safe trip back home.
祝你回家一路??
How'd you know I was leaving?
你怎么知道我要离?？
Everyone leaves Saigon.
大家都?离?西?
First the Chinese, then the French. Next, the Americans.
先是中?人 然后是法?人 再然后是美?人
After we fix it up, someone else comes, knocks it back down.
我?把城市修复 又?另一?人摧?它
You really need to bone up on your American history, fella.
小子 你?重修美??史
Every country America goes to war with,
美?每一次与某??家??
we leave it in better shape than we found it.
那?家在我?离??都比原?更好
But don't take my word for it, just ask the Germans and the Japs.
但?听我? 你?? 德?人和日本人就知道
If the Americans aren't winning,
如果美?不是占上?
then why would Hanoi call for a cease-fire?
?什么河?要求停火？
Maybe it's not a cease-fire. Maybe the enemy just ran out of bullets.
也?不是停火 也?只是??的子?用光了
I think you're wrong, Arthur. I think this is the real deal.
?瑟 我?得你?了 我?得?次是真的
The first steps towards legitimate peace talks.
?入真正和平?判的第一步
I believe this country wants what you Americans want.
我?????家想要的 和你?美?人想要的一?
I would hope so.
希望如此
I mean, half the people in the city we saved from bombed-out villages.
?城里一半人都是 我??被炸平的村庄里救出?的
We opened our doors to them
我?向他?敞?大?
when they were running away from the commies.
他??在躲避共党
Maybe they weren't running away from the commies.
也?他?不是在躲避共党
Maybe they were just running from the bombs.
也?他?只是在躲避炮?
Well, well, the blustering beer boy is back.
?怒的啤酒男孩回?了
I agree with him.
我同意他?的
They might smile at us, but they sure as shit don't want us here.
?然他??我?友善 但我肯定他?不希望我?在?
Maybe the cease-fire will make them happy.
也?停火??他??心
Cease-fire. When does this cease-fire start?
停火 ?是什么?候?始的？
Three days ago. There's a truce through New Year's.
三天前 春?期?休?
Well, someone forgot to tell that to the people living up in the woods.
有人忘了通知在?林里作?的人
What are you talking about?
什么意思？
They're still fighting like crazy up north.
北面仍在激烈交?
-Where'd you hear that? -I didn't hear it.
-你在哪听?的？ -我不是听?的
I saw it.
我?眼?到的
I was up in the mountains at LZ Jane with the First Air Cav.
我去?????的山地 ??第一空??兵?
Rubbish. They haven't let non-military personnel up there in weeks.
胡扯 他?几周前就不? 非?方人士去那?了
That may be true,
那也?是事?
but they didn't mention that when I was up there.
但我去的?候他??提到?一?
Let me see that.
?我看看
You silly twat. You're serious.
你???的混蛋 你是?真的
Yeah.
是
Hey, kid. What did you say your name was again?
嘿 小子 你叫什么??？
Chickie. Chickie Donohue.
奇基唐?修
Hien, Chickie Donohue is drinking on me. All night.
? 奇基唐?修今晚喝的都算在我?上
At the same time, Chick, I see 100 villagers killed
与此同? 奇基 我目睹100?村民被?
and only ten guns recovered.
而只找到了十把?
I know someone, one of our guys, got trigger happy.
我知道我???的某?人 碰到?后?性大?
And I got to report that story too.
我也得?道??故事
But see, that's the stuff that the press can't get enough of.
可是你瞧 媒体最喜??道?种事
That's all you guys report. That's what pisses me off.
你?只??道?种事 我气的就是??
It's not the whole story.
那不是全景
I don't know. Maybe if some of you guys lost as many friends as I had,
不知道 也?如果你? 像我一?失去?么多朋友
you'd feel a little differently.
你??有不同的感?
Those names behind the bar??
吧台后面的那些名字
that's the names of the journalists who've been killed so far.
是目前?止?生的所有?者
Friends of mine. Friends of everyone in this room.
我的朋友? ??房?里所有人的朋友?
But then why do you guys just report the bad stuff?
那?什么你?只?道?面消息？
That's what we hear back home.
我?在??听到的全都是?些
I mean, doesn't that hurt us? Like, as a country?
那不是?我?有害?？?害?家
The truth? The truth hurts us? No.
真相？真相??害我?？不
The truth doesn't hurt us. It's the lies.
真相不??害我? ?言才?
The lies and the conspiracy to distort the truth, that's what hurts America.
扭曲事?的?言和??? 才是?害美?的?西
You've seen the soldiers we've got out here.
你也看到了?扎在?里的士兵?
They're just kids. Good kids being patriots.
他?都是些孩子 ??的好孩子
Doing what their country asks. And I want the truth told for them.
遵??家的命令 而我想?了他??出真相
The people running this war, they're not patriots.
主???的那些人才不是??者
They're politicians. And they deal in the currency of lies.
他?是政客 ??就是家常便?
And if the lies continue,
如果任由?言??
they're just gonna keep sending boys out here to be killed
他?只???派孩子??里送命
to justify the boys who already got killed.
好假?已送命的孩子死得合理
And every GI that dies??
每一?死去的美?大兵
is what, 50, 60 Vietnamese?
?50、60?越南人的命？
And they're not soldiers.
他?并不是?人
They're moms and dads. Children. Little babies.
他?是爸?、儿童、?儿
You sure got some weird fireworks out here.
?里的爆竹?真奇特
That ain't fireworks, man. They're tracer rounds.
那不是爆竹 哥? 是曳光?
-Where you going? -The embassy.
-你去哪？ -大使?
-I'm going with you. -No, it's too dangerous.
-?上我 -不 太危?了
Hey, I need to get my papers or I can't fly out tomorrow!
嘿 我得拿到文件 否?明天?法乘?机
Come on.
走
Wait!
等一下
It could be VC.
可能是越共
-No, don't shoot. -Don't move.
-不 ??? -??
Don't shoot.
???
Yeah.
是
Hey!
嘿
Wait, yeah?
等等 好?？
（媒体）
Both of us.
??都是
-Yeah? -Go!
-可以?？ -走
Come on.
走啊
Soldier, what's the word?
士兵 什么情?？
Saigon's under attack.
西?遭??了
Viet Cong are everywhere. They got half of Cho Lon.
到?都是越共 半?堤岸市被他?占?
We got to get to the embassy.
我?必?去大使?
Forget it. There's fighting on every block and Charlie has the embassy!
?想了 每?街?都在?火 越共占?了大使?
-That's not possible. -Let's move!
-那不可能 -快走
Hey! Can you get us closer to the embassy?
嘿 能送我?去大使?附近?？
No, I told you. Get your asses out of here before you--
不 我?了 赶快离??里 趁你?…
Chick!
奇基
Oklahoma?
?克拉荷?？
Oklahoma!
?克拉荷?
Hieu! Hieu!
孝…
Chickie! Get out of the street!
奇基 快离?街道
He's dead! Move!
他死了 快走
No.
不
You okay?
你?事吧？
Yeah.
?事
Don't forget to breathe.
?憋气
I had this coming.
?是我活?
You know, when I was a kid,
你知道 在我小?候
if I did something wrong like lie to my mother or,
如果我做了什么坏事 比如?母??? 或是
you know, sneak into the teacher's office to steal the test answers,
溜?老?的?公室偷考卷答案
hocking candy, or whatever??
或是?糖果什么的
God always found a way to make me pay for it, you know?
上帝?是能找到?法 ?我付出代价 你知道?？
Like, I'd make an error in the big game, or I'd break my leg or something.
比如?我在重要比?中犯? 或摔?腿之?的
I'm telling you, man. I never got away with nothing. Nothing.
真的 哥? 我???有 ?幸逃?被? ???有
First time I had sex, I got crabs.
我第一次做? 就被?染了?虱
She blamed me.
她?怪我
Smuggling beer into a war zone??
偷偷?啤酒???
that's not the smartest thing I've ever heard of.
?不是我听?最?明的行?
It's certainly not the worst either.
?然也不是最糟糕的
Hey, Chick.
嘿 奇基
Let's go see what the world looks like today. Come on.
我?去看看今天的世界是什么?吧 ?
Coates, you were right. The cease-fire was bullshit.
寇特 你是?的 停火根本是假的
NVA came in with 80,000 troops. Attacked over 100 cities and towns.
北越??了八万?? 突?100多?城?
How did they get in here?
他?怎么??的？
VC sappers blew the wall open.
越共工兵把?炸穿了
That wall?
那堵?？
Our guys blew that out. After the VC was already in here.
那是我?的??炸的 ??越共已???了
The military just briefed us. The VC blew it open and piled in.
?方??我??了?? 越共炸??后入侵
The military must be mistaken.
?方一定是弄?了
I saw it with my own--
我?眼?到…
Oh, God. Please tell me we didn't drop an atomic bomb.
老天 ?告?我那不是我??投的原子?
No. Someone just blew the ammo dump at Long Binh.
不 有人炸了隆平的???
-Shit. -Where are you going?
-要命 -你要去哪？
I got a friend in Long Binh! I got to get over there!
我有朋友在隆平 我得去那里
You don't even know how to get there.
你都不知道要怎么去
I'll follow the mushroom cloud!
我朝蘑菇云的方向走
Chickie, they're not gonna let you in. All right?
奇基 他?不??你?去的 好?？
They will if I'm with you!
如果你也? 他?就?了
This one's got keys. I'm going. Are you coming?
?一?有?匙 我要去 你一起?？
Push over. Come on. Push over. Hold that.
坐到旁? 快? ?位子 拿好
I'm telling you,
我?真的
I watched one of our tanks pull up and blast a hole in that wall.
我看到我?的一?坦克停下? 在?上炸出了一?洞
I believe you.
我相信你
Well, then why would the military say that it was the VC?
那?什么?方?是越共做的？
There's a lot of wars going on in Vietnam. Most of all, the public relations one.
越南有各种各?的?? 最主要的是公??
The enemy blasting a hole in the wall is an easier sell
?人在?上炸出一?洞要比
than some kind of VC inside job, you know?
越共??玩??道的故事更可信 ?吧？
（加德士）
（隆平 美?????）
Hold it, cowboy. Identification.
慢? 停下 小子 出示身份
Arthur Coates. Look magazine.
?瑟寇特 《看?志》的
All right. They're clear.
好 他?可以?
Just get anything. Get over here and help.
有什么拿什么 ?????忙
I'm gonna look for my friend!
我去找我朋友
Hey.
嘿
Put this around your neck. Anybody asks you, just say you're press.
挂在脖子上 有人?起 就?你是媒体人?
-Hey! Bobby Pappas. You know him? -No.
-嘿 ?比帕帕斯 ??他?？ -不
-New York kid. New York kid. -No, I'm sorry.
-??人… -不 抱歉
Do you know where I can find Bobby Pappas?
???比帕帕斯在哪？
No idea, man. A lot of hurt people out here.
不知道 ?里很多人受?了
-Well, is there an infirmary somewhere? -Yeah, building 8.
-?里有??室?？ -有 8??
There you go.
?
They're gonna take good care of you.
他??好好照?你
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
I'm just looking for a friend.
我只是在找一?朋友
-You can't be in here. -It's okay. I'm with the press.
-你不能?? -?事 我是媒体人?
You think being with the press makes it okay?
你?得媒体人?就可以??做？
Get the hell out of here.
快出去
Come on. Give me a break, please.
拜托 ??我 可以?？
I've come all the way from New York to look for a friend.
我大老??????就是?了找朋友
He might have just got killed.
也?他??生了
Just trying to find out if he's alive or not.
只是想知道他是否?活?
What's his name?
他叫什么？
Bobby! Holy shit. Thank God.
?比 我的老天 感?上帝
Really? They had to flatten my entire base to get you to visit me?
真的？要炸平我的整?基地 你才肯?看我？
Goddamn, it's good to see you.
?死的 ?到你真高?
Heard a rumor you were coming. Bringing beer or some shit.
我听?你要? 送啤酒什么的
Yeah.
?
How you doing? You okay?
你?好?？?事吧？
I'm still alive. Better than nothing.
?活? ?比死了?
You shouldn't be here, Chick. It's not safe.
你不???里 奇基 ?不安全
Don't worry, I got a flight out of Bien Hoa tonight.
??心 我今晚去?和乘?机离?
I don't got any papers, but I'm sure I can weasel my way on.
我?有文件 但肯定能找到?路
There are no flights out of Bien Hoa. VC torched the place.
?和不?有?机 越共把那里炸?了
Then where can I fly out?
那我在哪里能乘?机？
You can't. The whole country's grounded for commercial air.
哪都不能 整??家的商?航班都禁止了
Only military's allowed in and out.
只有?方?机能?出
-For how long? -Who knows?
-要禁止多久？ -?知道？
Hey.
嘿
It's just a little thank you from everybody back home.
?是我?家?所有人?你的一???
For what?
?了什么？
For what? For this. For all this.
?了什么？?了?? ?一切
For putting yourself on the line for us.
因?你?我?大家在前?抗?
And a goddamn beer's supposed to make it all okay?
一罐?死的啤酒就能??一切?好？
Listen, Chickie, all right. I got a ton of shit to do.
听? 奇基 好了 我?有一堆事
Okay, we got to find a place for you to lay low before you get yourself killed.
好了 在你送命前 我?得找?地方?你藏起?
Do the phones still work around here?
?里的???能用?？
Okay. Can you just say that for me one more time?
好的 可以再重复一次?？
Tan Son Nhut.
新山一
Okay, great. Thanks. Yeah, I will be there. Thank you.
好 很好 ?? 我?去的 ??你
Is there any way that you can get me a ride to Tan Son Nhut?
你可能找到?送我去新山一?？
Why?
?什么？
Because I got a connection there, and he can help me out.
因?我在那有?熟人 他能?我
-Yeah, sure. -Thanks.
-是 ?然 -??
Commander General William Westmoreland
?指?官威廉威斯特摩?
described the embassy attack as a Viet Cong defeat.
?大使???一事??越共的失?
In my opinion, this is diversionary to his main efforts,
我???是???西 ?人?忽略他的主要行?
which he had planned to take place in Quang Tri province.
他?划在?治省采取的行?
"Diversionary"?
???西？
They didn't just attack the embassy, they attacked the whole damn city!
他?不只??了大使? 他???了整?城市啊
"Diversionary."
“???西”
Chickie. Come on. Let's go.
奇基 走吧 ?
-Hey, let's go. -What?
-嘿 走吧 -什么？
-I got us a way out. -A way out of where?
-我找到离?的?法了 -离?哪里？
Vietnam. I called a friend. He's pulling some strings for us.
越南啊 我??上一?朋友 他??我?走后?
I don't need to get out of Vietnam.
我不需要离?越南
What? What are you talking about?
什么？你在?什么？
I'm a war correspondent, Chick.
奇基 我是?地?者
This is a war. Somebody's got to be here to see what's going on.
?是?? ?得有人在??做??
Well, yeah. I get that. I get that, but this is just for a few days.
是 我明白的…但就?几天而已
You can come back as soon as things cool down.
情?好?后你就可以回?
Chickie, let's go.
奇基 走了
Don't be dumb, Arthur. This ain't a war no more.
?瑟 ?犯傻 ?已?不是??了
It's mass murder.
?是大屠?
That's what war is, Chick. It's one giant crime scene.
奇基 ??就是如此 一?大型犯罪??
Come on, Chickie. Let's go. I got to get back here. I got a job to do.
走吧 奇基 快? 我?得回? 我有工作
Hey, take care of yourself.
嘿 你保重
You too, Arthur.
你也是 ?瑟
Hey, when you get home, do me a favor.
嘿 你回家后?我?忙
Take a bath.
洗?澡
This will get you to Manila, sir. Then you're on your own.
?台?机?送你去?尼拉 先生 然后就要靠你自己了
Thanks, Habershaw. This is most appreciated.
??你 哈勃肖 你?了我大忙
Well, we're all on the same team. At least, I'd like to be.
都是自己人 至少我希望以后?是
I hope you'll let Langley know about this.
希望你把?事告??利
-Langley? -Headquarters.
-?利？ -?部的
Right. Right, I will. Actually, I'm gonna write him a letter.
?…我?的 其?我??他?信
Thank you. Thank you so much.
?? 太??你了
Look, Habershaw, I got to come clean.
哈勃肖 听? 我必?坦白
I'm not CIA.
我不是中情局的
Yeah, right.
好吧
No, really. I'm not.
不 真的 我不是
You're not?
你不是？
No.
不是
So??
所以
What are you?
你是什么人？
I'm nothing.
我?都不是
You guys are the fucking best.
?是你??些家伙?害啊
I don't even want to know.
我都不想知道是怎么一回事
Thanks, Pappy. I appreciate you taking care of me out here.
??了 帕皮 多?你照?我
-I'll see you back in the neighborhood. -Yeah, of course.
-我?回家? -是 ?然
You got a good heart, Chickie. It's your brain that I'm worried about.
奇基 你的心?很好 我比??心的是你的?子
This life's just a crapshoot, huh?
人生真是荒?啊？
And assholes like you and me live, while Reynolds and Minogue die.
你我??的混蛋活? 雷??和米?格?死了
Mate, Tommy could still turn up.
哥? ?姆?是可能?身的
He's gone, Chick.
他死了 奇基
Tommy, they found him.
?姆 他?找到他了
You sure?
你确定？
Yeah.
是
No way! Chickie!
天啊 是奇基
Get your ass over here.
快?我??
Hey.
嗨
Hey, look who it is.
嘿 瞧瞧??了
-Chickie? -Chickie!
-奇基？ -奇基
-Hey. -Son of a bitch, he lives.
-嗨 -算我?鬼 他?活?
-He came back to settle his tab. -No.
-他回??酒?了 -不是
So how was the trip? You must have had a ball.
旅途如何？一定很精彩
A ball? He was in a war, for Chrissake. It must have been hell.
精彩？老天? 他去的是?地 一定很可怕
Yeah. I mean, it must have been hell.
? 一定很可怕
And if you ever want to talk about it, ever, I'm here for you.
如果你想聊聊 任何?候 我洗耳恭听
And if you don't, I won't.
如果你不想 我就不听
Jesus Christ. You flip-flopping son of a bitch.
天啊 你????的混蛋
I missed you.
我很想你
You hear about Tommy?
你听??姆的事了?？
The kid died a hero.
那孩子死得光?
So how was it, Chick? Really.
奇基 情?到底如何？
Yeah, are we kicking ass and taking names?
? 我?是不是大?全胜了？
No.
不
What? Well, what do you mean?
什么？什么意思？
I mean, it's tough to make sense of anything over there.
在那?很?判?到底是什么情?
Well, that's what war is. It's a messy business.
??就是?? 很复?
Yeah. Yeah, but Colonel, all due respect, this is different.
是的…可是 上校 恕我?? ?一次不同
It's??
?一次…
It's chaotic.
非常混?
They all are. But it's a controlled chaos.
??都很混? 不?是有控制的混?
Not this time. The chaos over there isn't under control.
?次不是 那里的混?是失控的
It's not under control at all.
完全失控
Look, I know our granddads and our dads,
听? 我知道我?的祖?和父?
they went over to Europe to save the world.
?渡重洋 到?洲拯救世界
And I would put today's guys up there with them any day.
我?今天的?人?与他?一? 值得敬佩 ?是?然的
And I mean any day.
毋庸置疑
But I'm not so sure we're saving the world this time.
可是我不确定?一次我?是在拯救世界
Well, right or wrong, it sounds like you need a drink.
???? 听起?你需要喝一杯
Chickie, grab a stool. First one's on me.
奇基 找?凳子 第一杯算我的
Maybe the first couple.
前几杯都算我的
Thanks. But I got to go do something first.
?了 但我得先做一件事
Chickie.
奇基
I'm sorry I couldn't get these to him, Mrs. Minogue.
很抱歉我?能把????他 米?格太太
It's okay.
??系
I'm proud of you for going over there, Chickie.
奇基 你去到那里了 我很?你自豪
No one else would do that.
任何其他人都不??么做
It was pointless.
?么做很?意?
It didn't help no one.
??到任何人
It helped us. Everyone in Inwood.
?了我?啊 英伍德的每?人
It felt good knowing that someone was over there, checking on our boys.
知道有人在那? ?候我?的小伙子? 感?很好
Take these.
??你留?
Tommy would want you to have them.
?姆一定?希望你留?
No.
不行
I'm the one who talked Tommy into going.
是我?服?姆??的
What? No, he wanted to go.
什么？不 是他自己想去的
No, he didn't.
不 他不想
I knew Tommy was scared. Everyone knew.
我知道?姆害怕 大家都知道
So, I talked him into it.
所以我?服了他
I don't know why. I didn't want him to be afraid.
我不知道?什么 我不希望他感到害怕
But I should have let him be afraid.
但我??任由他感到害怕的
I should have let him listen to himself
我???他听?自己的?心
instead of listening to me.
而不是听我的
I'm sorry.
?不起
-Yeah, I think so. -I can--
-是 我也?得 -我可以…
Guys.
各位
Hey.
嗨
Do you know what you've put us through?
你知道大家被你害?了?？
We've been worried sick. Don't ever do something like that again.
我??心极了 永??再做?种事
I won't.
不?了
So did you give them their stupid beers,
所以你有?有把啤酒送?他?
or did you drink 'em all before you got there?
?是到之前自己喝完了？
They got the stupid beers.
啤酒送?他?了
Well, I'm sure it meant a lot to them.
那?他???一定很有意?
You okay?
你?好?？
Got to change a few things up.
我得做出一些改?了
Such as?
比如呢？
A little less drinking. A little more thinking.
少喝一? 多想一?
You really gonna quit drinking?
你真的不再喝了？
I said "less drinking".
我?的是“少喝一?”
I saved the last one for you.
最后一罐是留?你的
（?姆柯林斯、瑞奇杜根 ?文?克?恩和?比帕帕斯）
（全都平安??）
（他?最后都戒酒了）
（算是吧）
（奇基唐?修最??有成?警官）
（或是在?球??花生）
（但他的确?高中??了）
（之后?哈佛大?肯尼迪政府?院??）
（奇基后?成?城市?工）
（??隧道的建筑工之一）
（最?成?）
（??立法和政治主任）
（真正的奇基在????）
（?在的小伙子?）
（杜根 帕帕斯 奇基 柯林斯 ?克?恩）
（改?自?翰“奇基”唐?修）
（和J.T.莫洛伊的著作）
（?姆米?格主??出自己的生命）
（以拯救他的指?官）
（和???友的性命）
（民??愿?他?授???章）
字幕翻?：易?